<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bradonomics | The homepage of Brad West</title>
    <description>Web Developer • Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu Nerd • Marine Corps Veteran</description>
    <link>https://bradonomics.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://bradonomics.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 16:23:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 16:23:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.1</generator>
    
    
    
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Busy?</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is not enough to be busy. So are the ants. The question is: What are we busy about?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/busy/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/busy/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>How is David Sedaris Famous?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to be a better storyteller. It’s hard. Storytelling in general is hard, but ending a story, that seems almost impossible to do well. And it’s not only me; I do a good bit of reading and most people seem unable to end a story with any kind of conclusion or punch line. Most just stop, like the author ran-out of words or couldn’t be bothered to continue. I’m not sure if this is an editing problem or perhaps a psychological problem and ending a story is really that difficult and those who do it well are just better writers than the rest of us. I decided to read some books on the craft and see if I could learn a few tricks, a better way to think about storytelling in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first book I picked up was &lt;em&gt;Long Story Short&lt;/em&gt; by Margot Leitman. In the opening chapter Leitman is describing how she got into storytelling and how she was having a discussion with her agent: “What about David Sedaris? He sells books, and does live tours where he just reads his true stories, and he’s a household name. I’d like to be the next David Sedaris.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Sedaris isn’t a good storyteller. Wikipedia says he’s “an American humorist,” but he’s not funny. And he can’t end a story better than anyone else. I’ve read pieces of many of his books; pieces because I can’t get through them, they’re uninteresting. How is David Sedaris famous? This is not a rhetorical question. If you like him, please email me and explain yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/how-is-david-sedaris-famous/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/how-is-david-sedaris-famous/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Single Function Devices (or Why I Don&apos;t Have a Cell Phone)</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I got my first cell phone in 2003 and was so disillusioned with the thing by 2005, I threw it away. I didn’t get another mobile phone until 2010—a Samsung Galaxy Spica—which I got only because I had started university and wanted a flash card app. I used that app for a few weeks and realized I preferred paper flashcards; or no flashcards at all, truth be told. I kept that phone to make calls till around 2016 when I decided I didn’t want to carry a cell phone anymore, and I haven’t had one since. It’s fun to talk about how I don’t carry a cell phone because, capital-T &lt;em&gt;They&lt;/em&gt;, can track you. The reality is much more mundane: it adds many things I don’t want in my life and very few things I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many things in your house did you make a conscious decision about? Did you consider the pros &lt;em&gt;and cons&lt;/em&gt; when you bought that alarm clock, that iPad, that exercise equipment? Did you consider if those purchases were getting you more of the things you want in your life? My decision to not have a cell phone &lt;em&gt;wasn’t&lt;/em&gt; conscious. Back in 2016 it was more a feeling, a feeling I couldn’t articulate yet, a general dissatisfaction with a device trying to be all things in one package. It was also requiring far too much attention—and I didn’t even have a data plan. I wanted to be more deliberate with the things I spent time on, or at least try. I wanted to spend time with friends, I wanted to spend time reading, I wanted to spend time walking in the park. A phone wasn’t getting me any of the things I wanted; in fact, it was distracting me from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear here, I’m not anti-technology. I’ve spent most of my career supporting and building computer systems. I love the internet—or at least the internet circa 2008—but something has happened in the last ten years that has got everyone distracted, and made them horrible dinner companions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started using a Kindle years ago when I was living in Thailand where English language books were hard to come-by and expensive when you could find them. I like the old model, the one they stopped making, the one that doesn’t have a touch screen and isn’t backlit. The only thing you can do with it is read. I’m typing this on an Alphasmart Neo, a word-processor that has a very small screen and doesn’t connect to the internet. The only thing you can do on it is type. I’m a bad speller, so when I’m at a cafe writing in my journal, I carry a Franklin electronic dictionary. The only thing you can do with it is look-up words. When I want to take photos, I use a Fujifilm X-T2. The only thing you can do with it is take photos. The thing is, I could replace all these devices with an iPhone, but I don’t because none of these devices require my attention. There’s no lights, no sounds. They do the &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; thing I bought them for and they sit quietly where I left them until I make the conscious decision to return to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think this is taking things a little too far, but I’m not trying to sell anything here. I’m not trying to convince you of an argument other than, be deliberate with your choices. Because if you don’t decide how to spend your time, your devices will choose for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/single-function-devices/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/single-function-devices/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Longing</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There&apos;s a longing, a craving to know more than we get to know. [Y]ou want a lot of interesting things to occur before you die; and it strikes you that rather than wait around for them to occur, you&apos;re going to have to arrange most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theparisreview.org/interviews/2511/jim-harrison-the-art-of-fiction-no-104-jim-harrison&quot;&gt;Jim Harrison, &lt;em&gt;The Paris Review&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jim-harrison-longing/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jim-harrison-longing/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Problem with Ideas</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The problem with ideas is that you can&apos;t decide to have them. Certain kinds of nonfiction can be made to happen. The writer who is diligent, observant, and inquisitive enough can always find a story: you read the paper, you watch the world, you ask enough questions, and sooner or later, there it is. You have to write it, of course, but it exists with or without you. There are decisions to be made—how best to unfurl the information, what to prioritize, whose perspective to privilege. But you do not have to invent the story, you just have to tell it. I&apos;m not saying it&apos;s easy. I&apos;m just saying it can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Ariel Levy, &lt;em&gt;The Best American Essays 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/problem-with-ideas/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/problem-with-ideas/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>On Marginalia</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a documentary called The Secret Life of Lance Letscher. Letscher is an artist. He keeps boxes of source material but purposely doesn’t organize it. He does this so he can find unexpected things when he goes back through it. This is the same reason I don’t make notes in the margins of books. It’s difficult to find new things or be surprised by something if your notes keep dragging you to previous thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/lance-letscher-marginalia/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/lance-letscher-marginalia/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>RSS Feeds vs Social Media</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you find interesting things on the web?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are old enough to remember the web before Google, you may remember how people used to run their own websites. They might publish interesting articles themselves, but they’d also include links to things they found and often would keep a blogroll. The good stuff would bubble to the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three things have happened in the meanwhile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google weponized links.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content farms have been busy filling the web with spam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big Social and everything that comes with that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this, I’d like to propose three things. First, create a blogroll and/or a canon on your personal site. Next, delete your social profiles. Don’t worry, you won’t become friendless and estranged from your family. Then, to fill the void, setup a feed reader with sites you actually like. If you are unfamiliar with feed readers, checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youneedfeeds.com/&quot;&gt;youneedfeeds.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/web-feeds/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/web-feeds/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>On Creativity and Theft</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The secret of theft, which is also called &quot;creativity,&quot; is you have to steal a bit from a lot of different places. You can&apos;t go to the same 7/11 every time because they’ll catch you. So you go to the photo shop, and you go to the gas station, and you go to that little hot dog stand that nobody goes to and by the end you&apos;ve stolen enough stuff from enough places that people think its yours.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalboardofreview.org/2018/05/qa-ethan-hawke-paul-schrader/&quot;&gt;Paul Schrader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/creativity-and-theft/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/creativity-and-theft/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>What Books to Read</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you only read the books that everyone else is reading, you can only think what everyone else is thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Haruki Murakami&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/what-books-to-read/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/what-books-to-read/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Kickstarter Books</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just stumbled on a book that made $64,000 on Kickstarter. How is this even possible? I’m not suggesting that it is not a fine book. I’m more curious if it’s something repeatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/craigmod/koya-bound-a-book-of-photography-from-japans-kuman&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ksr-ugc.imgix.net/assets/012/788/403/5f8b276f9389219e85dd8bd14b856ac4_original.jpg?crop=faces&amp;amp;w=1552&amp;amp;h=873&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;v=1472574574&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;q=92&amp;amp;s=36fbee374e7a83597f42198ec8417739&quot; alt=&quot;book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/kickstarter-books/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/kickstarter-books/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Frank Abagnale Story</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Frank Abagnale, the “Catch Me If You Can” guy, talks at Google:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe title=&quot;The Frank Abagnale Story&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/vsMydMDi3rI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/frank-abagnale-story/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/frank-abagnale-story/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Paginate a Dual Language Blog in Jekyll</title>
          <description>
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jekyll-dual-language/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jekyll-dual-language/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Randy Couture Story</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are unhappy with their jobs. A lot of those people want to start some kind of entrepreneurial endevor to break away. Most people look to their hobbies for ideas. They think, as I did, that they already know so much about this topic and already spend so much time doing this thing, it should make a good business. The problem for many is their identity is so closely tied to that activity they can’t bear the thought of failing at it. When you’re known as the guy who does &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&apos;sans-serif&apos;&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;PASSION, it can be hard to pursue &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&apos;sans-serif&apos;&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;PASSION for money. What happens if you fail? Will you still be the guy who does &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&apos;sans-serif&apos;&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;PASSION?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years my &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&apos;sans-serif&apos;&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;PASSION was mixed martial arts. At first, I wanted to be a professional fighter. After my first training camp and first fight, I decided maybe I didn’t want to be a pro fighter. I still liked combat sports so I looked for other things I could do in the industry. Things that didn’t involve being in the ring. I tried a few but never succeeded at any. In hindsight, I think it had a lot to do with my identity being so closely tied to MMA that made it difficult to put myself out there in that industry. Randy Couture made similar remarks in an interview once. He had come out of nowhere and beaten some of the top fighters in the world. And he’d done it at an age most experts assumed too old to be competitive at the upper levels of the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couture was a wrestler from a young age. He went to Oklahoma State University where he was a three-time NCAA Division I All-American. He was also a three-time Olympic team alternate. But as happens with a lot of athletes who don’t have a pro league in their sport, he started looking for a why to make money. Most people get a job or, if they’re famous enough (someone like Michael Phelps), they get sponsors. Randy decided to give MMA a try. It was close enough to wrestling he assumed he’d be able to do well and make a little money. To everyone’s surprise, including Randy’s, he was not only good but very good. His style of wrestling was exceptionally effective for MMA. In Greco-Roman wrestling, you aren’t allowed to grab below the waste. Because of this Randy was very good at tying up his opponent’s arms and still being able to hit them from a standing clinch. But mindset also played a huge roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interview, Couture said he noticed many of the fighters were very nervous in the changing rooms before going to fight. He remembered this was how he felt before wrestling matches. He would be super nervous, to the point of vomiting before most of his matches. He’d spent a lifetime preparing to be a wrestler … he &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a wrestler. It was important to him that he do well. All his friends and family knew him as a wrestler. But for MMA, well, that was just a side gig—a way to make money—no real pressure there. So with an unusual skill-set and having not spent unnecessary energy, he went out and performed well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to say you should never pursue your hobbies or passions as businesses, but be cautious. There’s a lot of overlap in Randy’s story and the writings of Cal Newport in the book &lt;a href=&quot;/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If Randy’s story intrigues you, Cal’s book will probably be interesting also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know enough about human psychology to say why we sabotage our efforts when we care strongly about an outcome, but it seems like we do. I’m not sure if there’s a lesson in here, but I think there’s something. Maybe it’s this: Find business ideas on the fringes of your passions, slight deviations from your primary interest. Then the pressure to perform will be lessened and maybe you can relax enough to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/randy-couture-story/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/randy-couture-story/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Work Hours</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Working ten hour days allows you to fall behind twice as fast as you could working five hour days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Issac Assimov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/work-hours/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/work-hours/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Driverless Cars, The Early Days</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Early automobiles caused as much controversy as driverless cars do today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.1843magazine.com/technology/driving-lessons&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://1843magazine.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/styles/article-main-image-overlay/public/201610_TE_CAR_001-header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;car crash with trolly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/driverless-cars-early-days/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/driverless-cars-early-days/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>An Anti-Travel Story</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I boarded the Etihad plane in Dallas and was immediately reminded why American airlines suck. There was a large display in the seat in front of me with various entertainment options. There was a USB port, ethernet port, and some other port I’ve never seen before. There was also an electrical plug in the back of the seat for charging laptops ...or hair irons I guess. In the seat was a pillow with a perforated middle section that, once torn, became a neck pillow. There was a blanket, headphones, and a kit with a toothbrush, socks, earplugs, and an eye mask. I had plenty of time to look through all this as there was a problem with a family a few rows in front of me. Something to do with their luggage from what I could tell. After about an hour of deliberation with the crew, they decided to leave the plane. Of course, this meant their luggage in the bottom of the plane needed retrieving, so we were on our way about two hours late. Now mind you, I only have an hour and twenty minutes layover in Abu Dhabi. I was a little nervous I’d be spending the night there, but those concerns abated quickly when dinner came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a mistake eating at Popeye’s in Dallas. The Etihad crew served dinner shortly after takeoff. It was quite the spread. I ate till I was about to bust. It was good—exceptional for airplane food. I got a little sleep and was given a second meal before landing, this was also good. The sleep, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a fan of going to the bathroom on airplanes, or getting out of my seat, or being on an airplane in the first place. Even though this was a 16-hour flight that turned into an 18-hour flight, I figured it best to go to the bathroom once I was safely on the ground. We landed and parked in the back 40 so we had to take a bus from the plane to the terminal. Once we were at the terminal there was an extra security check for connecting passengers. After I got finished with all that, I checked the monitors to see which gate I was leaving from and noticed that my flight was already boarding; not only that but it said “last call.” So instead of going to the bathroom, or browsing the fifty duty-free shops I passed en-route, I went straight to the gate and boarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t the last person to board, but close. I was also by the window with a middle-aged Arabian couple seated between me and the aisle. I saw other people going to the lavatory before we started to move so I probably had time to go then. I decided I’d just wait till we were in the air before disturbing the couple that had just moved to let me in the seat. No sooner than the seatbelt sign turned off, the drink cart came. As soon as that was done it was time to eat again. Due to some particularly bizarre serving strategy, the few rows in front of me didn’t get served. The crew realized the mistake and passed out their trays after everyone else had already finished. This delayed the trash collection and as soon as that was done, they turned out the lights. The Arabian couple pulled up their blankets and settled in. I thought to myself, &lt;em&gt;it’s only a six-hour flight. And I don’t have to go that bad. I should be able to hold it&lt;/em&gt;. I did fall asleep for a short time, but when I woke up I knew there was no way I was making it to Bangkok. Thankfully the Arabian fella had to go also and when he got up, I followed. You know how those airplane toilets hold the water until you flush? I thought I was going to have to flush mid-stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before landing, a crew member came by to inform me that my bag hadn’t made it on the plane since the connection was so short in Abu Dhabi. He said to talk to a desk agent once I was in Bangkok but of course, there was no one around when I got off the plane. I found an airport information desk while I was heading for immigration and they said after I’d cleared immigration I could go to the sixth floor and speak with Etihad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head down the hall where there are two signs: “immigration” and “visa on arrival.” If you showed up without a Visa, expecting to get one &lt;em&gt;on arrival&lt;/em&gt;, which of those signs would you follow? I got in the visa-on-arrival line. I was approached by someone who was, no doubt, being paid to make this an efficient process and asked where I was from. They said I didn’t need a Visa and that I should go to immigration. It’s not really their fault. They weren’t hired for their decision-making abilities, they were hired to follow directions. The guy who designed those signs and thought they said all there was to be said, and then hired someone once that was clear as mud—&lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; should be fired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got through immigration and started looking for someone to help with my delayed bag as I had forgotten everything the girl at the information counter said to me. I finally found a counter with an 8.5”x11” sign that had my name and flight number on it in 8pt font. Whoever decided that was a good way to signal people in one of the world’s largest airports should also be fired. I couldn’t give the girl at the counter an address for delivering the bag as I didn’t know Zine’s address &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; since addresses aren’t given in Thailand in the number, street, city fashion they are in most of the world. Addresses in Thailand almost always involve explanations. Things like: turn left at the road with the big tree on the corner. In the end, I was given a phone number to call and a baggage claim number to reference when I had an address for them to deliver the bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zine told me to meet her at gate 3 on the second floor. I proceeded through gate C and checked that I was on the second floor. After roughly 30 hours of travel, gate C equaled gate 3 in my head. After scanning the crowd I walked over to a phone charging station and tried to connect my phone to the cell network. It seems that having been gone for a whole two and a half months my SIM card didn’t work anymore. I had that number for six years and now it didn’t work? Thanks a lot DTAC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fiddling with the phone for about a half hour I decided to find an information desk and have Zine paged. Mind you at this point I still think I was at the right spot and she’s gone off to do some shopping or maybe something came up and I should take the train. It only occurs to me now, days removed, that I could have called her via Skype with the airport WiFi. But before I got to the information desk Zine popped out of nowhere ...or gate 3 as she pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is a slightly modified version of a complainypants email I sent to my family about my return trip to Thailand after having spent the summer in the USA. I finally got my bag back; nothing was broken or missing. And DTAC was able to reinstate my number. So I guess everything worked out in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/anti-travel/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/anti-travel/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Seven Years of Business Failures</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved to Thailand in 2009. My intent was to use my GI Bill, experience a new culture, and most importantly, build a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mma-podcast&quot;&gt;MMA Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002 I was introduced to Mixed Martial Arts fighting. Until then, I had liked working in IT. But those VHS tapes changed everything. In 2005 I had my first MMA fight. The short version of the story is, I decided that I didn’t want to be a professional fighter after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I didn’t want to be a pro fighter, I still wanted to do something in the fight industry. I was a fan of podcasting and saw the success people like Lloyd Irvin had selling products in the space. I thought I’d try something similar. I had a slow road to learning Jiu-Jitsu and thought there must be a better, faster way to learn. I decided to call my podcast White Belt Radio. I bought the domain and set up all the social media profiles. Then the guys at MMA Diehards decided to start a show with the same name. Worried about a lawsuit and subconsciously looking for any excuse to procrastinate I decided to change my name. I had the idea for the show in 2009, but with all this, I wouldn’t publish anything till 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to call the show Fight Map. I did 4 or 5 episodes and stopped. A few years before I’d torn the PCL in my left knee and wasn’t able to play Jiu-Jitsu. I also felt that not being in Los Angeles or Las Vegas was a real disadvantage since I was more interested in Mixed Martial Arts and Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu than Muay Thai. It was enough for my lizard brain to freak-out and for me to shut it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;niche-sites&quot;&gt;Niche Sites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been following &lt;a href=&quot;https://empireflippers.com/&quot;&gt;The AdSense Flippers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nichepursuits.com/about-me/&quot;&gt;Spencer Haws&lt;/a&gt;, and a few others and watched as they set up a boatload of small websites monetized with Google AdSense or Amazon affiliate links. It seemed easy enough so I found some keywords I thought I could rank in Google. Kirby Vacuums and Big 10 Tires. I bought some domains and set-up the sites. It didn’t last more than a month before I started feeling bad for writing webspam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s that? You didn’t know niche sites were spam? Well, it’s not as bad as YouTube comments, but no one is happy when they land on a niche site. I mean really … what could I say about Kirby Vacuums that Kirby hasn’t already published? And Big 10 Tires? They were bought by Pep Boys. Believe me, Pep Boys has said everything they care to say about what’s going to happen with Big 10 after the acquisition. I might be able to rank for this, but who cares? I wasn’t happy writing articles to game the system, so I shut them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;english-language-school&quot;&gt;English Language School&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011 I moved to Bangkok to attend the &lt;a href=&quot;http://auathai.com/&quot;&gt;AUA language school&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/second-language/&quot;&gt;failing Thai classes at university&lt;/a&gt;. I was already sold on the system but hadn’t considered teaching. I met another American interested in the ALG system and we started tutoring. I thought I’d try my hand at a bricks and mortar business. If this internet stuff wasn’t going to work, maybe this was my path to entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a seed group of students and started tutoring at a university library. The students seemed to like it, so we started looking for office space to start a proper school. We talked with a lawyer to discuss the business structure and what might work for us but were discouraged to find our options to operate in Thailand very restricted. We heard from a friend about establishing as a “school” under the Ministry of Education instead of a business under the Ministry of Labor. Talking with the Ministry of Education we learned that to start the process we’d need to present our lease agreement, our curriculum, and paper receipts from students—meaning the Ministry of Education was asking us to operate illegally. I was OK with the idea, but my partner was married and wasn’t keen on getting deported should someone start snooping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went looking to the internet again thinking we could make videos of our classes and sell the videos. We made a test video and sent it to our students. The ALG system is very dependent on feedback so I need to see my students to know if I’m understood. If you are listening to a language you don’t understand and you get lost, it’s difficult to get back into the story. We didn’t have the feedback when making the video so we had to assume understanding. None of the students liked it. They had a hard time following since we weren’t repeating ourselves like we would in the classroom. We concluded that teaching language, in person or on the internet, wasn’t in the cards and gave it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;english-teaching-website&quot;&gt;English Teaching Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still interested in silent period teaching methodologies, I thought I’d start a website about teaching English. I set up EnglishInAsia.com and started a podcast interviewing English teachers around Asia. I quickly realized I didn’t care about the standard teaching experience in Asia. Not only that but, it has been talked about many times on many other sites. I wondered if I could get the teachers to write their stories so I could publish them on my site and sell ads against the views. I started looking for teachers who might be willing to write about their experience and reached out. I asked if they’d like to write for me, but was rejected by everyone who even bothered to reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot from this project about ads and software to run the ad buys. As I look back over my failed projects every one has taught me something. It’s a slog, but I didn’t know what else to do. This project lasted a few months and I shut it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;marketing&quot;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things converged and I decided to try my hand at marketing. First, when I was attending the AUA school in Bangkok I became friends with the director and he asked for my help with their online ad spend. They were using Google AdWords and while it was bringing leads, it wasn’t optimized. I made some tweaks and after a few months was saving the school $200/month with no noticeable loss in registrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second was my failed English in Asia website. I knew the major reason I was unable to get people to write for me: I couldn’t sell the vision. I knew I’d need to get better at marketing if I was going to run my own business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was offered a “job” paying room and board at a homestay in northern Thailand and saw it as a chance to work on some marketing skills. I was intended to stay three months—I only made it two. I was told before going that the homestay was having a hard time attracting clientele. They had hired an agency but didn’t like the customers they’d sent and were looking for a better fit. Turns out they didn’t know what they were looking for, so I’m not sure the agency did anything wrong. It was difficult to come up with a strategy and have them change the target customer. After the third complete change in strategy, I decided to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months later I saw an email about a “growth hacker” position with a local company and applied. The company was willing to give me a shot even though I had little in the way of experience. I did email marketing and the like for about six months when I knew it wasn’t the company that was the problem, it was the work. Marketing, while important, is not fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-development&quot;&gt;Web Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was about this time that the company shifted focus and wanted to update their website. Lucky for me that all the front-end developers were away on vacation. I was given the job to build their new website and did well enough to be given client work. I spent about a year and a half building websites for them. When there were no projects I spent my days building my development skills. Then, after two years with them, I was laid-off. Luckily the fires had been relit and computing had once again become fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computers are fun again and I’m back to my old habits—trying to start another business. This time with software, but more importantly creating real value. As I look back over this list of failures the obvious observation is that none of these ventures offered value. I was hoping to game the system to get money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May of 2020 I started my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://webniyom.com/&quot;&gt;Web Development Agency&lt;/a&gt;. My hope is, this time, I’ve created something that others find valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/failures/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/failures/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The American Dream; in Northern Europe</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2016/07/nordic-american-dream-partanen/489032/&quot;&gt;The American Dream is alive and well—in Northern Europe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think Americans have any idea how much they really pay in taxes, how that compares to other countries, or what we get versus what they get for those taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/american-dream-in-europe/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/american-dream-in-europe/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Jekyll vs WordPress, a Speed Comparison</title>
          <description>
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jekyll-wordpress-speed/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jekyll-wordpress-speed/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Getting Stuck in Life</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Joe Rogan on getting stuck in life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe title=&quot;Getting Stuck in Life&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/e8jIZ3NB7s4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/getting-stuck-in-life/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/getting-stuck-in-life/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Adventures in Open Source</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using Linux as my sole desktop operating system since 2015. For years I called myself a Windows fanboy, even when some people claimed that wasn’t a thing. I didn’t come to that conclusion lightly. I spent years looking for something better but ultimately decided that Windows just worked. It was easy to setup, didn’t require “dependencies,” and didn’t hang or shut down as often as everyone said. Of course saying this type of thing got the Mac users riled. I was told I should give Apple a try. “You’ll be so much more productive,” they said. So a few years ago I did try using a Mac. I borrowed a friend’s and intended to spend at least one whole workday using it … what a disaster that was. I couldn’t get it to do seemingly basic stuff. I couldn’t even get windows to maximize. A different friend finally got me to understand why most people make the switch to Mac so easily and I’d failed to grasp even the basics. You see, I’d been a Windows system administrator for years. I earned my living making Windows do whatever I wanted. So the gap I was trying to cover was much larger than most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with this love affair with Windows, I’d always felt like open source was a better option. I was introduced to Unix in 1999 when I attended my basic job school for the Marines. While I was at my first duty station there were a few Unix servers, but of course, I wasn’t allowed to touch them as I had no idea how they worked. They were these magic boxes that displayed cryptic messages and because of that were fascinating. I asked if I could attend the Unix System Administrator course at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marine_Corps_Communication_Electronics_School&quot;&gt;Marine Corps Communication Electronics School&lt;/a&gt;. This was an 8-hour per day, month-long course of nothing but Unix. I was hooked and wanted to run it at home and learn even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried loading Linux on my home system. This was about 2002 and RedHat was the big player at the time. I got the OS installed with little trouble. The problem was every time I wanted to install some software, I couldn’t find it for Linux. Once I finally found an alternative, it would require me to manually install a dependency. OK, no problem. I type the command in the terminal to install the dependent package and was prompted that this software also had a dependency. OK, still not a problem …until it was. After trying to install 5 or 6 dependencies only to be told that each dependency also had dependencies was too much. I bailed on Linux and went back to Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still liked the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; of Linux so every 2-to-4 years, when I’d buy a new computer, I’d try installing it to see what was new. I tried various distributions just to make sure it wasn’t that particular flavor that was the problem, but the same manual dependency search would ensue and I’d wipe the drive and install Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 2013 I got a new computer and did the same thing. This time it was Ubuntu and this time something was wrong. The install process looked almost like Windows. It had a great graphical interface that was professionally designed, it prompted me in the graphical interface for my computer name, username, location, etc. Once the system was loaded I tried to install software. What’s this? A software manager? And get this, I wasn’t prompted to install dependencies. Perhaps this wasn’t Linux I was running. Perhaps I’d downloaded the wrong thing. Of course, I knew that wasn’t true. I’d been following the development of Ubuntu and had even tried one of their earlier versions. But things were different now. This was a great operating system. It would even automount the CD drive, something Apple and Microsoft had figured out no less than a decade earlier. There were still a few hiccups. The same thing my friend had observed before about my attempt to switch to Mac. There were still things I didn’t know how to do with Linux that I could easily do with Windows. So I decided to dual boot. I’d leave Ubuntu on my computer but install Windows also—to get real work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime in early 2015 I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://keithcu.com/wordpress/?page_id=407&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;After The Software Wars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Keith Curtis and started thinking more about open source code, where society is, and where it could be if we’d all work together. I’m not a great developer. I can’t write C or C++ code, the languages that power most of the really big, really fast things you read about in magazines like &lt;em&gt;Wired&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Popular Mechanics&lt;/em&gt;, so I can’t help from that end. But I can use open source programs and send usage statistics and crash reports so those super smart people who work on those programs can have data to work with and make improvements. It’s a small thing but it’s what I can do for now. And on top of that Linux makes me feel like a hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/linux-adventures/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/linux-adventures/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reading List — May 2016</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I just don’t find enough good stuff to write Reading List posts that often. That’s why it’s been a few years since I’ve written one. Below are seven books I rated above average in that time. Seven whole books. It is almost depressing that there are not more good books out there …or that there is no decent recommendation engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read Bill Bryson’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/walk-in-the-woods/oclc/926879835&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Walk in the Woods&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a few years before and didn’t care for it, so I’m not sure what prompted me to pick up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/in-a-sunburned-country-with-a-new-appendix-on-the-sydney-olympics/oclc/635271676&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a Sunburned Country&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but it was a great read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having so much fun with &lt;em&gt;In a Sunburned Country&lt;/em&gt; and thinking about a pending trip back to the US, I decided to read Bryson’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/im-a-stranger-here-myself-notes-on-returning-to-america-after-twenty-years-away/oclc/915866829&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m a Stranger Here Myself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Also highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve rekindled my interest in computing, and Linux specifically, in the last year or so and decided to read a few books on open source software. Paul Graham’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/hackers-painters-big-ideas-from-the-computer-age/oclc/934323016&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hackers &amp;amp; Painters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was great. Most of his essays are available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/articles.html&quot;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt; but I’d never read most of them. Graham writes in a way that is easy to understand even when the subject matter is complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there was Eric S. Raymond’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/cathedral-and-the-bazaar-musings-on-linux-and-open-source-by-an-accidental-revolutionary/oclc/1027047759&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cathedral &amp;amp; the Bazaar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; a perennial hacker favorite. Raymond uses his tenure as the lead developer of Fetchmail to help you understand the thinking of an open source hacker. If you only read one book about Linux and open source software, make it this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting excited about programming after all these years I knew I’d need some exceptional focus. Cal Newport’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/deep-work-rules-for-focused-success-in-a-distracted-world/oclc/986975350&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; covers just that and gives a decent overview of how you can implement deep work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/selling-the-invisible-a-field-guide-to-modern-marketing/oclc/149066543&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Selling the Invisible&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Harry Beckwith had been on my Kindle for a while and, for a lot of people, software is just as “invisible” as services. I thought the overlap between running a service business and running a software business would make this worth reading, and it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just in case you thought I haven’t read any fiction, Barry Eisler’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/graveyard-of-memories/oclc/861206917&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graveyard of Memories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was great. I think it’ll be the last book in the John Rain series and that makes me a little sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: July 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
A new John Rain book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/zero-sum-a-john-rain-novel-book-9/oclc/1109785766&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zero Sum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, was just published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-articles&quot;&gt;Web Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the best of the best web articles I’ve read over the last few years. It’s quite a few links, but they are all good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cracked.com/article_18544_how-the-karate-kid-ruined-modern-world.html&quot;&gt;How ‘The Karate Kid’ Ruined The Modern World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.samharris.org/blog/item/the-future-of-the-book&quot;&gt;The Future of the Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://l2mastery.com/blog/linguistics-and-education/methods/stephen-krashen/&quot;&gt;Interview with Stephen Krashen: Linguist, Researcher &amp;amp; Education Activist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://solomon.io/why-im-done-with-social-media-buttons/&quot;&gt;Why I’m Done with Social Media Buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2014/01/how-to-hack-okcupid/&quot;&gt;How a Math Genius Hacked OkCupid to Find True Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thenitai.wordpress.com/2014/03/12/why-you-might-not-want-to-incorporate-in-the-usa/&quot;&gt;Why You Might Not Want to Incorporate in the USA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nevernorth.com/start-a-movement/&quot;&gt;Build a Brand and Start a Movement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsomers.net/blog/dictionary&quot;&gt;You are Using the Wrong Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2012/02/mac-mcclelland-free-online-shipping-warehouses-labor&quot;&gt;I Was a Warehouse Wage Slave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nohatdigital.com/blog/redefining-money/&quot;&gt;Redefining Money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://christinacacioppo.com/blog/learning-online&quot;&gt;Learning Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://priceonomics.com/the-man-who-smuggles-traders-joes-into-canada/&quot;&gt;The Man Who Smuggles Trader Joe’s into Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/love.html&quot;&gt;How to Do What You Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/say.html&quot;&gt;What You Can’t Say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5978475/how-to-pick-a-career-you-actually-like&quot;&gt;How to Pick a Career You Actually Like&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unfubared.com/blog/2009/05/09/controlling-your-environment/&quot;&gt;Controlling Your Environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eatingacademy.com/personal/wired-think-scientifically-can-done&quot;&gt;Why We’re Not Wired to Think Scientifically (and What Can Be Done About It)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://waitbutwhy.com/2014/05/fermi-paradox.html&quot;&gt;The Fermi Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2qXgPfMGG8E&quot;&gt;I’ll Fight You For The Library (YouTube)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gq.com/story/the-last-true-hermit?printable=true&quot;&gt;The Strange &amp;amp; Curious Tale of the Last True Hermit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thoughtcatalog.com/ryan-holiday/2015/05/how-to-learn-the-art-of-speed-reading/&quot;&gt;How To Learn The Art Of Speed Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.alinelerner.com/what-happens-when-you-stop-relying-on-resumes/&quot;&gt;What Happens When You Stop Relying on Resumes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pmarchive.com/guide_to_career_planning_part3.html&quot;&gt;Where To Go and Why&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@stewart/we-dont-sell-saddles-here-4c59524d650d#.5awqvtw61&quot;&gt;We Don’t Sell Saddles Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/&quot;&gt;On the Phenomenon of Bullshit Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conversionvoodoo.com/blog/2010/04/increase-your-conversion-rate-by-making-your-site-uglier/&quot;&gt;Increase Conversion Rate by Making Your Site Ugly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrgreen.am/affiliate-marketing/the-ugly-truth/&quot;&gt;The “Ugly” Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://idlewords.com/talks/website_obesity.htm&quot;&gt;The Website Obesity Crisis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://priceonomics.com/how-i-went-from-leading-the-egyptian-revolution-to/&quot;&gt;How I Went From Leading the Egyptian Revolution to Making Minimum Wage in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/28121/they-write-right-stuff&quot;&gt;They Write the Right Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-may-2016/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-may-2016/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Jekyll Categories on GitHub Pages</title>
          <description>
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jekyll-categories/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jekyll-categories/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Take to the Oars</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If the wind will not serve, take to the oars.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Latin Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/take-to-the-oars/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/take-to-the-oars/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>How to Screw Up Your Life by Getting Promoted</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Building something interesting requires a surplus of time and money. Salaried jobs provide neither.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20200220141023/http://thestartuptoolkit.com/blog/2012/12/how-to-screw-up-your-life-by-getting-promoted/&quot;&gt;Rob Fitzpatrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/screw-up-your-life-by-getting-promoted/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/screw-up-your-life-by-getting-promoted/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>I&apos;ll Fight You For The Library</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;“I’ll Fight You For The Library” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://taylormali.com/&quot;&gt;Taylor Mali&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe title=&quot;I&apos;ll Fight You For The Library&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/2qXgPfMGG8E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/fight-you-for-the-library/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/fight-you-for-the-library/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Moving to GitHub Pages Using Jekyll</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started digging into GitHub, one of the first things I noticed was &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. After getting GitHub setup on my computer (I was on Windows at the time so I setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://desktop.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub’s Desktop Client&lt;/a&gt;) I made a repository for my personal page, bradonomics.github.io and pushed an HTML file as a test. That was exciting so I started digging for alternative ways to use GitHub pages. I had already been running Bradonomics via static HTML files for a few months as part of an SEO experiment, but when I wanted to make one change to my navigation menu, I needed to update 30+ pages …not fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are my notes on the process of getting to know Jekyll and getting it setup on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-jekyll-now&quot;&gt;“Installing” Jekyll Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly found the “blog aware static site generator” call &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, but since I’ve never used Ruby I wasn’t sure how to get started. If you’re in this boat, check-out Barry Clark’s project called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jekyllnow.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Now&lt;/a&gt;. The basic idea is to fork an existing repository with a functioning Jekyll site, and then customize it to make it your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I poked at this for a couple days, and while it wasn’t quite what I was looking for, it did give me a great intro into the Jekyll system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;starting-over-with-skinny-bones&quot;&gt;Starting Over with Skinny Bones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most platforms have galleries showcasing theme designs and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll/wiki/Sites&quot;&gt;Jekyll is no different&lt;/a&gt;. I quickly found &lt;a href=&quot;https://mademistakes.com/&quot;&gt;Michael Rose&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmistakes.github.io/skinny-bones-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Skinny Bones&lt;/a&gt; theme. I poked at that for a few days trying to get it to conform to the basic design of my existing theme, but ultimately wasn’t getting where I wanted to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scrapping-it-all-to-merge-bradonomics-with-medium&quot;&gt;Scrapping it all to Merge Bradonomics with Medium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending enough time with other themes to understand the system, I decided to scrap the whole thing and start fresh. I knew the design I wanted was going to be unlikely to come from hacking at a pre-built theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to keep a lot of what I liked in my old theme and apply some design concepts I’d seen around the web to give me more space. I was feeling a bit constrained before and wanted a full-width header. Since the Medium design had always been attractive to me, I added a full-width image as they have on some of their pages. This didn’t allow for the same navigation menu as I had before so using Chris Coyier’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/off-canvas-menu-with-css-target/&quot;&gt;“Off Canvas Menu”&lt;/a&gt; tutorial along with some help from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xanthir.com/b4Kn0&quot;&gt;Tab Atkins, Jr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://meyerweb.com/eric/thoughts/2011/09/12/&quot;&gt;Eric Meyer&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to add it to a hidden menu bar that slides in from the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-jekyll-locally-to-avoid-30-git-pushes-per-day&quot;&gt;Installing Jekyll Locally to Avoid 30 Git Pushes Per Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the line, I got tired of doing all those pushes when I was trying to get the CSS just right. Barry’s Jekyll Now project does a lot to get you running quickly, but it’s a pain during the development process to work on a live site. I decided to install &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyll-windows.juthilo.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll for Windows&lt;/a&gt; despite the “this might not work” warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have only one comment to make regarding the install: make sure you put the Ruby files in a directory without spaces. Since Windows installs by default to the “Program Files” directory, I put the Ruby files there. Turns out, Ruby doesn’t like the space in the directory name and wouldn’t load. Once the install path was changed, everything worked as advertised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-github-for-hosting&quot;&gt;Using GitHub For Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had the Jekyll theme looking like I wanted, I thought it would be nice to use GitHub Pages as the new host for Bradonomics as the files were already there and a speed test said it was just as fast as my current web host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this guide from GitHub, &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-github-pages/&quot;&gt;“Setting up a Custom Domain”&lt;/a&gt;, and this guide from David Ensinger, &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidensinger.com/2014/04/transferring-the-dns-from-namecheap-to-cloudflare-for-github-pages/&quot;&gt;“Transferring DNS to CloudFlare for GitHub Pages,”&lt;/a&gt; to work perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/images/CloudFlare-DNS-for-GitHub-Pages.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/images/CloudFlare-DNS-for-GitHub-Pages.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CloudFlare with GitHub Pages&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;What my settings looked like when I was finished.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update September 2015:&lt;/strong&gt; Some time in early 2015, only a few months after publishing this, I moved back to WordPress. I was unable to get categories to work with Jekyll. It seems Jekyll doesn’t support something as basic as this, though there are some tutorials on the web where people have hacked a workaround. I’ve spent two days trying these tutorials and combing the code of sites that have categories, but still can’t get it to work. As much as I like the idea of Jekyll, I’m not smart enough to pull it off. So until someone writes a better tutorial or Jekyll starts supporting categories natively, I’ll stick with WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update December 2015:&lt;/strong&gt; I finally got categories working and bradonomics.com is back on Jekyll and hosted with GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update November 2019:&lt;/strong&gt; The update above was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://webniyom.com/jekyll-categories/&quot;&gt;manual implementation&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually I moved to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-archives&quot;&gt;jekyll-archives plugin&lt;/a&gt; since I started doing local builds and only pushing the built site to Github Pages. For clients I’ve needed a way to paginate these archives. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sverrirs/jekyll-paginate-v2&quot;&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2 plugin&lt;/a&gt; has both archives and pagination.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jekyll/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jekyll/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Your Life Sucks</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Remember, Mondays are fine. It&apos;s your life that sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Ricky Gervais&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/your-life-sucks/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/your-life-sucks/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Gardens and Libraries</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you have a garden and a library, you have everything you need.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Cicero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/gardens-and-libraries/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/gardens-and-libraries/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Baseline Report: Chiang Mai, Thailand</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Pat Flynn was the first blogger I saw publishing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/tag/monthly-income-report/&quot;&gt;monthly income reports&lt;/a&gt;. Shortly after, a lot of entrepreneurs, especially those in the affiliate space, jumped on the bandwagon. When these reports first became popular I thought they were great, but quickly saw the limitations. As long as you intend to do something similar to the guy publishing the report they can be helpful, but what if your business is completely different?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, I moved to Thailand with the goal of starting a business. My idea was to leave the US where my savings (and GI Bill) would go further—but Thailand was largely arbitrary. Shortly after I moved, Dan Andrews started publishing a podcast and talking about creative baselining and whether it was better to bootstrap a business from the Philippines or Bali or Thailand. Here are some of the articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tropicalmba.com/thailand-vs-bali-vs-philippines/&quot;&gt;Thailand vs. Bali vs. the Philippines. What’s the Best Spot for an Internet Entrepreneur?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tropicalmba.com/for-the-bold-one-of-the-cheapest-ways-to-start-your-online-business/&quot;&gt;One of the Cheapest Ways to Start Your Online Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tropicalmba.com/cost-of-living-in-bali/&quot;&gt;Use Mobility to Win Back Your Time + The Real Cost of Living in Bali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a university student for most of the first five years I lived in Thailand. While this saved me from doing VISA runs, my living expenses included tuition. Over the years, I’ve averaged around $1,000 USD in expenses per month. It didn’t matter if I was paying tuition or, in the year I took off, doing VISA runs every three months, my expenses were the same. But not having a journal I can’t be certain of my expenses and that’s why I decided to start The Baseline Report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that a report of living expenses would be more useful to bootstrapping entrepreneurs than an income report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-numbers-or-how-much-did-it-cost-me&quot;&gt;The Numbers (or How Much Did it Cost Me?)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1yTC82Nee10J9M567YW90gV7vSFrvHhONJEXw0If8IZ8/&quot;&gt;raw numbers here&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a Google Spreadsheet with multiple tabs for the different months I was tracking expenses. The first tab called “report,” is the overview of each month with the category average in column B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, this report is the expenses for two people. I found it difficult to list my expenses separately from my girlfriend’s expenses in most cases. But to give a good guess at single living expenses check out the second tab called “Single Expenses.” On this, I added the average expenses from the report tab and guessed at how much of each category I’d be paying if I lived alone (column C). Column D is the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-first-condo-in-chiang-mai&quot;&gt;My First Condo in Chiang Mai&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first six months I lived in Thailand I was renting a condo for 10,000 baht. It was owned by an English lady and she had posted the details on the internet. It was near my university and available so I took it. Below are some photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Hillside-Condo-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Hillside-Condo-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Condo in Chiang Mai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Hillside-Condo-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Hillside-Condo-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hillside Condo Chiang Mai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Hillside-Condo-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Hillside-Condo-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hillside Payap Condo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cheaper-options&quot;&gt;Cheaper Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more expensive options and cheaper options. Below is a dormitory style room in an apartment building near Payap University. It’s not the nicest place, but it does have air conditioning and a hot shower. A room like this will run about 2,300-2,800 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Racha-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Racha-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Racha Apartment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Racha-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Racha-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Racha Condo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Racha-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/baseline-report/Racha-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dorm near Payap University&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a blog post when I was in university called &lt;a href=&quot;http://payapuniversity.blogspot.com/2010/12/dorm-alternatives-condos-houses.html&quot;&gt;Dorm Alternatives: Condos &amp;amp; Houses&lt;/a&gt;. It holds up well even four years later. And, for single women, there are &lt;a href=&quot;http://payapuniversity.blogspot.com/2011/02/women-only-dorms-blessing-place.html&quot;&gt;Women Only Dorms&lt;/a&gt; near the universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this gives you some better idea of what life is like (or &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be like) in Chiang Mai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are looking for an apartment anything you can find online in English is going to be a bit expensive. Knowing what part of town you want to live in and walking to each building to inquire will generally get you a better price than using the internet. Having said that, if you are willing to stumble in Thai, there is a site called &lt;a href=&quot;//www.renthub.in.th/&quot;&gt;RentHub&lt;/a&gt;, that is really good. While they do have a language selection for English, you’ll probably get better results if you read Thai (or have a friend read it for you). If there is a way to email or message them, you would be well advised to use that method instead of calling as most Thais are better at reading and writing than speaking English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tuition-and-visas&quot;&gt;Tuition and VISAs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thailand VISAs are an oft-discussed issue among expats. All of us are looking for a way to stay here and looking for the cheapest, most convenient way to do so. Here are a couple of options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people an ED VISA means a Thai language school and while looking for numbers to compare to my own, I found an article by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lengthytravel.com/studying-thai-in-chiang-mai-advice-from-a-long-term-chiang-mai-resident/&quot;&gt;Jeff Blum on Lengthy Travel&lt;/a&gt; discussing his situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Thailand VISA Comparison:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Day&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Activity&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;ED VISA&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Student VISA&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Trip to Vientiane&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5,450&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3,450&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;90&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Immigration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,900&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,900&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Immigration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,900&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1,900&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Totals&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Thai Baht&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9,250&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3,900&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-5,350&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;US Dollars&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;285&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-165&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Jeff’s article for more on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lengthytravel.com/studying-thai-in-chiang-mai-advice-from-a-long-term-chiang-mai-resident/&quot;&gt;difference between one year on a tourist VISA versus one year on an ED VISA&lt;/a&gt;. In that article he also discusses language school options in Chiang Mai and while &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/second-language/&quot;&gt;I’m not a big fan of the methods at those schools&lt;/a&gt;, it is a great resource for weighing your options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now let’s talk about ED vs Student VISAs. All things VISAs will likely change by the time you read this … and might change again by the time you finish reading this but, for now, ED VISAs are the standard three-month VISAs offered by language schools. If you are already in Thailand on a tourist VISA, you’ll need to visit a Thai consulate outside Thailand to switch to the ED VISA. But once you’re in Thailand on your ED VISA you can renew it, without leaving, so long as you continue paying the tuition at your language school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming a university student is slightly different. Most people enroll from their home country and apply for their VISA before coming. If you go this route you’ll get the same ED VISA as discussed above. Once your tuition has been paid during your first semester you will be given paperwork to switch to a Student VISA. This is a one-year VISA, although the first year it only extends you by nine months since the ED VISA gave you three already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope the graph above is making sense by this point. But one thing to note about that graph is that Jeff and I are only talking about VISA fees. In both of these cases, you’ll need to pay tuition. Tuition at Payap University, a private school in Chiang Mai, is between 55,000 and 80,000 per semester depending on your major. Payap has one fee per semester no matter how many classes you take. A cheaper option is Ramkhamhaeng University, a public school in Bangkok, which charges per credit hour and will run about 30,000-40,000 per semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you are working and don’t have time for classes? You might be able to get a business VISA. I’ve spoken to a few people who’ve gotten a business VISA by contacting a Thailand law firm and explaining that they are looking to start a business in Thailand and need VISA sponsorship. The law firm will charge a fee to draw the papers, but then you’ll have the paperwork you need to get a one-year business VISA. (I have a feeling this option won’t be around much longer as the system is getting harder and harder to hack. But it does work as I’m writing this.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-numbers-or-how-much-will-it-cost-you&quot;&gt;The Numbers (or How Much Will it Cost You?)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s important when talking about how much it costs to live in a place like Chiang Mai that you don’t use blanket statements like “you can live a good life there on $1,000/month.” It’s better if you talk about what’s possible and what’s probable. It’s possible that you can live on $500-$600 per month—VISA runs included—I’ve done it for years. It’s more likely that you’ll spend more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dig around, find some reports and make your own average. You might find people living below the standard you want to live or living lavishly. Just use the numbers from the people who are living most like you want to live …and that’s how much it’s likely to cost &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; to live there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Jeff breaks down the cost of a Laos VISA run on his site. While I think the costs will be more than this for the average person, I’ll leave the numbers as he’s listed them. Another thing to note is most university students would get their VISA from their home country before coming and wouldn’t need to leave Thailand, hence the cheaper initial cost. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/baseline-report/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/baseline-report/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Self-built Cabin</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;93-year-old man lives in a cabin he built by himself, 5 miles from the nearest road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe title=&quot;Self-built Cabin&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/76364379?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/self-built-cabin/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/self-built-cabin/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Solar Freakin&apos; Roadways</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Solar Freakin’ Roadways!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe title=&quot;Solar Freakin&apos; Roadways&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qlTA3rnpgzU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/solar-freakin-roadways/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/solar-freakin-roadways/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Too Stupid to Learn a Second Language?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;After high school I joined the Marine Corps and my first assignment was to Okinawa. I had no real interest in going, but after some months Japan started to grow on me and I became interested in learning Japanese language. I got a few books and a CD set and started learning the basics, things like: “Are you open?” and “Where is the bathroom?” It was a struggle. I had a hard time remembering words. The worst part was, even when I could make myself understood, I couldn’t understand their reply. I still remember being at a World War II memorial and saying &lt;em&gt;hello&lt;/em&gt; to a woman in Japanese. She replied with a torrent of Japanese I had no hope of understanding. After a few months, the books found their way into a drawer. I didn’t really &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to learn Japanese, I was on a military base surrounded by other Americans. On top of that, I would be returning to the US in six months where Japanese would be less than useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I was back in the US I regretted not learning and pulled the books out again. If you think Japanese is hard where you’ve got easy access to native speakers, try learning it in the California desert. The results weren’t coming and I gave up even quicker than before. Two thoughts then occurred to me: maybe a romance language would be easier than an Asian language and maybe it would be easier to learn a language I believed would benefit me. With the large population of Hispanics in the US, I thought learning Spanish might get me a job. At the very least, I could talk with my neighbors. So I bought books and CD’s, just as before, and started again: “Are you open?,” “Where is the bathroom?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the same problem as before, even when I could make myself understood, I couldn’t understand their reply. But Spanish had two additional problems: it wasn’t exotic like Japanese and was therefore less interesting and I could tell it would be many years before my Spanish would rival my neighbor’s English—assuming that ever happened. Add to this the frustration I felt when I couldn’t remember the vocabulary and it was too easy to give up. It would be six years before I would attempt another language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, I moved to Thailand and enrolled in university. I had high hopes of learning Thai language. Not only was there a foreign language requirement for my degree, I’d have a proper class with teachers. My first semester I took Thai 1. I made a ‘C.’ Not bad, but not great. I was having the same problems as before. I could, on rare occasion, make myself understood but I couldn’t understand anything said to me and I had a hard time remembering the vocabulary. I couldn’t order food at the market without gestures nor could I tell taxi drivers where to go. I continued trying and assumed, with the help of my teachers, things would come around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second semester I enrolled in Thai 2 and failed. Since this was the third language I’d failed to learn, I started to wonder, “Maybe I’m just too stupid to learn a second language.” But if that were true, there was nothing I could do about that. Since every method I’d tried was the same, I started looking online for something different. I found a few language blogs, people like Benny Lewis and others, who recommended I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fluentin3months.com/speak-it/&quot;&gt;start speaking more&lt;/a&gt;, use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaylanguagelearner.com/2012/01/09/language-learning-tip-using-paper-flashcards-effectivley/&quot;&gt;more flash cards&lt;/a&gt;, spend &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnthaifromawhiteguy.com/consistency-is-key/&quot;&gt;every free moment learning some aspect of the language&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t feel like more of the same was the way to go. Since Payap University offers a Masters in linguistics, they have a large section in the library for books on learning a second language. I thought if bloggers can’t offer something different, maybe academics could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first few days in the library, all I found was more of the same: more grammar, more drills, more practice. Then, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/natural-approach-language-acquisition-in-the-classroom/oclc/751657260&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Natural Approach&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by doctors Krashen and Terrell. They said grammar drills and flashcards weren’t only unnecessary, they might be preventing me from learning. I went online to find &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sdkrashen.com/&quot;&gt;books&lt;/a&gt;, papers and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3QyX9XhGX3s&quot;&gt;YouTube videos of Dr. Krashen&lt;/a&gt;. He talked of comprehensible input and storytelling; while I liked what he had to say, since it was altogether different from what I was getting in the classroom, I didn’t know what to do with the information. How could I get my teachers to stop assigning vocabulary sheets and tell more stories in Thai without translating? As I continued looking for a way to use Dr. Krashen’s ideas. I found that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://auathai.com/&quot;&gt;AUA Language Center in Bangkok&lt;/a&gt; was using a method based on Dr. Krashen’s theory—a method developed by a guy named Dr. J. Marvin Brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brown had been involved in language learning and teaching since 1944, but it was in 1962 after receiving his Ph.D. in linguistics that he started teaching at the AUA school in Bangkok. He taught there until 1980 and over those 28 years he was trying to teach English to Thais and Thai to non-Thais. In both cases, he failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his autobiography, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/brown-autobiography/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the Outside In&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he talks about the hopes he had of getting Thai students to speak English at a near native level. All the while he kept noticing things—things that would contradict his understanding of language learning. For example, he once observed that the main job of servants in Thailand was to listen and the main job of bargirls was to talk. Since servants had better English pronunciation than bargirls, it was reasonable that American Foreign Service students should have better Thai pronunciation than Mormon missionaries. So why was it that the missionaries had better Thai pronunciation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out the Mormon missionaries Dr. Brown was observing do their preaching in pairs. For the first six months in-country Mormon missionaries are known as “juniors.” During this time, they listen while the “seniors” do all the talking. They listen to their senior and the people they preach to and only once they become seniors do they start speaking Thai. The American Foreign Service students are encouraged to speak by their classmates, teachers, and family from the first day they arrive in Thailand. That doesn’t mean that the American Foreign Service students did poorly. There’s a story in Dr. Brown’s book about an American Foreign Service student giving a presentation at the AUA School after being in Thailand for only one year, and he was surprised how well the student spoke Thai. Dr. Brown started wondering how American Foreign Service students could achieve in one year what it had taken him five years to achieve. He even took some notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dr. Brown: 500 hours of study + 1 year in family = 50% (the grade he gave himself). American Foreign Service student: 100 hours of study + 1 year in family = 70% (the grade he gave them). He then solved the equation: 400 hours of study = -20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He laughed to himself—how could a career linguist believe this for even one second? How could it be that the more you studied, the worse you did?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the late 1970s Dr. Brown had run out of ideas. He’d tried everything he could to get students to speak their second language like their first. He decided to leave AUA and return to university in the United States. He had become interested in physics and hoped some ideas would be waiting for him in a field where he didn’t have “professional blinders.” But he’d need a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While studying physics, Dr. Brown also studied Chinese and Japanese with hopes of getting a job teaching one of them. Since he wrote the books most schools were using to teach Thai, he was over qualified to teach that, but was under qualified to teach either Chinese or Japanese. Finally, in his fourth year at university, he was given a chance to teach Japanese. Still using the “practice method” he used in Thailand, he had his students drill grammar and vocabulary. At the end of the semester when the student appraisals came back he read how much they hated him and his practice—even those who had done well. He was crushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Brown went to visit his colleague Adrian Palmer seeking advice. Dr. Palmer handed him a copy of &lt;em&gt;The Natural Approach&lt;/em&gt; by Krashen and Terrell. Dr. Brown had heard of Krashen’s ideas on language acquisition before but had always dismissed them. Now, at rock bottom, he decided to give them a try. He had another Japanese class scheduled the following term and, since he didn’t speak Japanese well enough, got a Japanese man to assist. Neither of them had ever taught a class like this and there were few models to follow. They struggled, awkwardly, through the term and at the end Dr. Brown braced himself for the student appraisals—they loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the students may have loved the class, it didn’t mean they were learning anything. Dr. Brown wanted to start a program to see what would happen if they continued using the method. He decided the best place to do this would be the AUA school in Bangkok. He talked with his former employer to see if they would entertain the idea. They agreed and Dr. Brown moved back to Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last term before Dr. Brown moved, he taught a Thai class at the university using the Natural Approach concepts he’d implemented the previous semester. With the help of his colleague Adrian Palmer, they developed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/listening-approach-methods-and-materials-for-applying-krashens-input-hypothesis/oclc/1078851198&quot;&gt;The Listening Approach&lt;/a&gt;, which later became Automatic Language Growth. The main deviation from Krashen and Terrell’s method was the silent period:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Krashen had said that the students shouldn’t try to say anything during the first ten hours. He called it the “silent period.” [Dr. Palmer] and I both agreed that the silent period should be lengthened considerably—perhaps by many times. If indeed “you learn to speak by listening,” why should they speak at all? Any time spent with the students speaking would be wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still remember reading Dr. Brown’s book for the first time after failing my Thai class at university. It must have been a similar experience Paul had on the way to Damascus. The idea that the more you tried the worse you’d be, resonated with me in a way I can’t explain. I threw away my dictionary and stopped speaking Thai. I called the AUA School in Bangkok to see if they had a program in Chiang Mai, but they didn’t. David Long, the coordinator of the Thai program, told me about a method for maintaining the silent period and getting the necessary input—a system they call &lt;a href=&quot;https://algworld.com/alg-crosstalk/&quot;&gt;Crosstalk&lt;/a&gt;. I tried using the system he described and also tried getting input from TV and movies but it wasn’t working like Dr. Brown had described in his book. Things were slow and I felt I had two options. Give up again or move to Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April of 2011, I moved to Bangkok and enrolled at the AUA School. Things were slow at first, and there were times I wondered if I’d ever learn a second language, but slowly I did start to understand. What really solidified my belief in Dr. Brown’s theories happened one day while ordering food. I was ordering a rice dish but used the word ขาว instead of ข้าว. It’s a common mistake. The thing is, most language learners don’t know they’ve made it. They need someone else to point it out. I knew as soon as it left my lips and made the correction. I knew it was wrong because I’d listened to people say it for hundreds of hours. A few similar events happened and I fell in love with the idea that language could be learned from stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/second-language/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/second-language/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reading List — July 2013</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;My introduction to Cal Newport’s book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-why-skills-trump-passion-in-the-quest-for-work-you-love/oclc/966671765&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was in a &lt;em&gt;Fast Company&lt;/em&gt; article which &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/follow-passion-useful-advice/&quot;&gt;I wrote about here&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been interested to read the book since but just haven’t made time. I finally got a copy of the book and the &lt;em&gt;Fast Company&lt;/em&gt; article does not do it justice. I wrote a review of the book; &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/&quot;&gt;you can read it here&lt;/a&gt;. Before you read my review I’ll preface it with this: if you’re struggling to find meaning in your work or looking for a new career, you need to read this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was thinking about career trajectory and was riding a wave of motivation after reading Newport’s book, I decided to see what Steven Pressfield had to say in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/turning-pro-tap-your-inner-power-and-create-your-lifes-work/oclc/798188052&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turning Pro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I was a little disappointed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/war-of-art-break-through-the-blocks-and-win-your-inner-creative-battles/oclc/955664049&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The War of Art&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a great book, and one I’d highly recommend, but &lt;em&gt;Turning Pro&lt;/em&gt; seemed, at best, an addendum—&lt;em&gt;The War of Art, Revised and Updated&lt;/em&gt; would have been better. If you’ve already read &lt;em&gt;The War of Art&lt;/em&gt;, you can skip &lt;em&gt;Turning Pro&lt;/em&gt;. If you’re deciding between the two, well…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still in the mood to read about career theories and since it was just published, I read James Altucher’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/choose-yourself-be-happy-make-millions-live-the-dream/oclc/994829404&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Choose Yourself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of the book was republished blog articles. Not that this is a bad thing. I hadn’t read them on his blog and I only noticed after I had read the book. The main premise of the book is to follow a “health” regimentation focusing on four areas: mental, spiritual, physical and emotional. I think it’s easy enough to learn the ideas on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2013/01/finding-your-goal-and-purpose-in-life/&quot;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt; and wouldn’t recommend the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two failed attempts to read different career theories and being disappointed, I thought I’d read Dan Pink’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/drive-the-surprising-truth-about-what-motivates-us/oclc/1082864831&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Newport referenced it many times in &lt;em&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt; and I thought it would be best to see where the research came from. It was a great follow-up to Newport’s book. In fact, I’d go so far as to say Newport took Pink’s research and molded it into a career advice book. That’s not to say Newport stole the ideas. Newport first wrote about what would become Career Capital Theory a year or so before &lt;em&gt;Drive&lt;/em&gt; was published. But &lt;em&gt;Drive&lt;/em&gt; gave him the research on motivation he needed to round-out his theory. If you’re interested in intrinsic motivation theories, &lt;em&gt;Drive&lt;/em&gt; will be a good read. But you’ll probably want to start at the back. In “Part Three,” he gives an overview; the theories and a some thoughts on applying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard good things about the meta-learning sections of Tim Ferriss’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/4-hour-chef-the-simple-path-to-cooking-like-a-pro-learning-anything-and-living-the-good-life/oclc/1089931549&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;4-Hour Chef&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and decided to give it a try. I skimmed mostly since I wasn’t interested in learning to cook but the parts of the book about how to learn skills quickly was very interesting. It’s a massive book and, what little I read in the section, gives a great introduction to cooking. He puts structure behind cooking so as not to intimidate the reader. It’s likely I’ll buy a hardback version to keep as reference for his ideas on meta-learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-articles&quot;&gt;Web Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the articles I found on the web this month that were interesting or educational. They are listed here in the order I found them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/how-to-read-more-a-lot-more/&quot;&gt;How To Read More — A Lot More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://observer.com/2012/11/out-of-reach-if-the-media-covers-you-youd-better-bring-an-audience/&quot;&gt;Out of Reach: If the Media Covers You, You’d Better Bring an Audience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/so-you-want-to-be-a-writer-thats-mistake-1/&quot;&gt;So You Want To Be A Writer? That’s Mistake #1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openculture.com/2013/05/ernest_hemingways_reading_list_for_a_young_writer_1934.html&quot;&gt;Ernest Hemingway Creates a Reading List for a Young Writer, 1934&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/07/20/how-to-self-publish-a-bestseller-publishing-3-0/&quot;&gt;How To Self-Publish A Bestseller: Publishing 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freakonomics.com/2011/05/04/deliberate-practice-how-education-fails-to-produce-expertise/&quot;&gt;Deliberate Practice: How Education Fails to Produce Expertise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2013/04/03/the-locust-economy/&quot;&gt;The Locust Economy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://qz.com/82743/a-phd-in-economics-is-the-only-one-worth-getting/&quot;&gt;A Ph.D. in economics is the only one worth getting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theamericanscholar.org/solitude-and-leadership/&quot;&gt;Solitude and Leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last one, Solitude and Leadership, is a must read if you have any intention of being a leader. Once you read it, I’d love to hear your thoughts. Email me at brad@bradonomics.com and let’s talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-july-2013/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-july-2013/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>So Good They Can&apos;t Ignore You — Book Review</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve long wondered why some people love what they do while others lead lives of mediocrity and boredom. I’ve spent a lot of time thinking about the topic as it applies to my life and those closest to me. I’ve read many books on the topic and spent many hours in conversation trying to crack the code if there is a code to be cracked. What’s interesting, most of the advice on the subject is the same. No matter how educated someone is or what their background or whether they have passion for their own job, everyone offers the same thing—forget about money and pursue passion. Everyone until Cal Newport that is…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal’s book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-why-skills-trump-passion-in-the-quest-for-work-you-love/oclc/966671765&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;So Good They Can’t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, opens with the story of a guy named Thomas. Thomas has spent a few years trying to find something he’s passionate about. He spent time teaching English in Korea, traveled through China, Tibet, and Africa before moving to a Zen monastery in mountains of New York. After two years at the monastery, Thomas felt as if he’d reached “the zenith of his passion,” as Cal puts it, and was again left wondering what he should do with his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following pages, Newport argues that finding your passion is not productive and might even be harmful. He argues that becoming skillful in a field will build passion. He gives examples from different people and from different industries using skills to build passion instead of first discovering passion to pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rule-1-dont-follow-your-passion&quot;&gt;Rule #1: Don’t Follow Your Passion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-passion-of-steve-jobs&quot;&gt;The “Passion” of Steve Jobs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did Steve Jobs follow a passion into computing or not? To hear Newport tell it, he didn’t. Cal tells the abridged version of Jobs’ path to becoming the founder of Apple computer. He tells of his studies at Reed College, his practice at the Los Altos Zen Center, and his time spent on the All-One commune. He concludes that if Jobs had followed his passion as he advised in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D1R-jKKp3NA&quot;&gt;Stanford commencement speech&lt;/a&gt;, “we would probably find him today as one of the Los Altos Zen Center’s most popular teachers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the book, Cal will introduce a three-level pyramid that can be used to find mission in your work. I see no reason why this pyramid can’t be used to determine if general interests have any career viability. It seems to me that’s what Jobs was doing. He was using this system of small schemes to see if there was real, long-term, interest in the field. He was also testing, as Derek Sivers will introduce later, which of these ideas were profitable enough to pursue as a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;passion-is-rare&quot;&gt;Passion Is Rare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This forms the basis for Cal’s entire argument that following passion is not useful advice. He talks about the research where Yale professor Amy Wrzesniewski conducted surveys of college administrative assistants. Wrzesniewski found that “these employees were roughly evenly split between seeing their position as a job, a career, or a calling.” She then wanted to understand “&lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they saw their work so differently, and discovered that the strongest predictor of an assistant seeing her work as a calling was the number of years spent on the job.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The holes in this argument are so apparent to me I have a hard time explaining them. It seems that those who like their work and see it as a calling are either lucky in having chosen the field or suffer from a sunk cost bias and the longer they are in the job the worse it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other research comes from Daniel Pink in his book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/drive-the-surprising-truth-about-what-motivates-us/oclc/1082864831&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where he talks about Self-Determination Theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Self-Determination Theory (SDT), which is arguably the best understanding science currently has for why some pursuits get our engines running while others leave us cold.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;SDT tells us that motivation, in the workplace or elsewhere, requires that you fulfill three basic psychological needs—factors described as the “nutriments” required to feel intrinsically motivated for your work:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Autonomy: the feeling that you have control over your day, and that your actions are important&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Competence: the feeling that you are good at what you do&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Relatedness: the feeling of connection to other people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport then suggests this helps explain Wrzesniewski’s findings: “Perhaps one reason that more experienced assistants enjoyed their work was because it takes time to build the competence and autonomy that generates enjoyment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the book, Cal will introduce two other factors, control and mission, that are needed to develop passion for your work. Out of these five traits: autonomy, competence, relatedness, control, and mission, how many are needed to feel “intrinsically motivated” about your work? Administrative assistants can’t achieve much autonomy, they’re assistants and are therefore working on their boss’s projects and not their own. Since the workers surveyed worked at colleges they have to be at the school from 9-to-5 so they have little control. And I find it hard to believe that administrative assistants feel much of a mission. So what’s left? People often answer surveys the way they wish things were and not the way things actually are. The assistants who claimed this was a calling had spent many years in the position and who wants to admit that they’ve spent all that time bored at a job that’s not very fulfilling? It sure seems like a sunk cost bias to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;passion-is-dangerous&quot;&gt;Passion Is Dangerous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more I studied the issue, the more I noticed that the passion hypothesis convinces people that somewhere there’s a magic “right” job waiting for them, and that if they find it, they’ll immediately recognize that this is the work &lt;em&gt;they were meant to do&lt;/em&gt;. The problem, of course, is when they fail to find this certainty, bad things follow, such as chronic job-hopping and crippling self-doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the book starts to turn for me. Even if the rest of his argument about following your passion is weak, this part seems solid. He talks of interviews conducted for &lt;a href=&quot;http://roadtripnation.com/&quot;&gt;Road Trip Nation&lt;/a&gt; and people profiled in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/quarterlife-crisis-the-unique-challenges-of-life-in-your-twenties/oclc/970542109&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quarterlife Crisis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; expressing feelings of restlessness because they couldn’t be sure if this job was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; job. Since I’ve experienced these exact emotions, it’s starting to feel like Newport might be on to something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rule-2-be-so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-or-the-importance-of-skill&quot;&gt;Rule #2: Be So Good They Can’t Ignore You (Or, the Importance of Skill)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of Steve Martin’s appearance on &lt;em&gt;The Charlie Rose Show&lt;/em&gt; where he gives the career advice to “be so good they can’t ignore you” and the story of Jordan Tice learning a new guitar riff leads Cal to make an interesting comment. When talking about the difference between what he’s labeled the Craftsman Mindset and the Passion Mindset, he says the Passion Mindset focuses on what your work offers &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; and makes you hyper-aware of what you don’t like about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s starting to hit a nerve…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-career-capital&quot;&gt;The Power of Career Capital&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have to pick a job by some means, so how can we get a list of jobs that might qualify to be good jobs? Jobs where we can apply the Craftsman Mindset? Cal offers three traits that define great work: creativity, impact, and control. He then goes on to profile three people who’ve put in the work necessary for their jobs to give them these traits: Steve Jobs, Ira Glass and Al Merrick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To get [his current job], Merrick realized he needed a rare and valuable skill to offer in exchange [for the freedom to go surfing at a moments notice]. Once he had surf pros like Kelly Slater riding his boards—and winning—he became free to dictate the terms of his working life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that what gave Al Merrick the freedom to “dictate the terms of his working life” was being an entrepreneur. Had he followed the same path shaping boards for Billabong, gotten just as good and shaped competition winning boards for Slater, do you think Billabong would have let him go surfing in the middle of the day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or what about Steve Jobs? Had he been buying circuit boards in the purchasing department of another company do you think the owner of that company would have let him spend half the day designing mp3 players? What allowed these guys the freedom they had was owning the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll concede that Ira Glass, host and producer of &lt;em&gt;This American Life&lt;/em&gt;, accomplished most of what made him successful while he was an employee. Although he wasn’t able to pursue most of that until he was the boss and even then he had little control or autonomy. Although I would assume what Newport means to convey by using these examples is that Glass would never have been the boss, and Jobs and Merrick would never have owned their own companies had they not been good at what they did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-economics-of-great-jobs&quot;&gt;The Economics of Great Jobs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal next introduces Lisa Feuer who quit her job in marketing to open a yoga studio. Feuer quits, takes out a $4,000 loan to pay for a certification course, and opens Karma Kids Yoga. I’m sure you can guess where this story is going…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To contrast Lisa’s story Newport introduces Joe Duffy, a former artist who moved into the marketing industry. As Duffy started to “chafe at the constraints of corporate life,” he returned to his roots and started drawing logos and brand icons. What’s interesting to note about Duffy’s story is it took twenty years to gain the control and monetary success to buy, and spend time at, a hundred-acre retreat in Wisconsin which is told as the success point in his story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s unspoken in Lisa Feuer’s story, I suspect, is she hated her job so much she couldn’t wait twenty years. Not that moving to a new industry with no skills was a good idea. What Lisa Feuer should have done is use those advertising and marketing skills a little while longer, even if she hated that job, and work with an entrepreneur in the yoga industry to build her entrepreneurship skillset—similar to what Duffy did. Or at least, gotten a job as an instructor for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s clear from this chapter is that moving to an unknown industry where you have no skills is a bad idea. But I’m still left wondering how to find a job that will provide meaning in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-craftsmanship-fails&quot;&gt;When Craftsmanship Fails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an email from a blog reader, Newport realized that “certain jobs are better suited for applying career capital theory than others.” So he devised a list of three traits that disqualify a job. Jobs that won’t provide a good foundation for building work you love:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The job presents few opportunities to distinguish yourself by developing relevant skills that are rare and valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The job focuses on something you think is useless or perhaps even actively bad for the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The job forces you to work with people you really dislike.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel this is a good starting point but what about individual variation among traits? I mentioned earlier that I can’t imagine administrative assistants feeling much of a mission. But that’s just the way I look at mission. Some assistant’s mission might be in supporting others and being the person that makes a good leader a great leader. That has just as much value as my idea of mission but without considering your biases you could land yourself in a job that won’t provide a good foundation for building a great career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only four pages in the whole book are dedicated to this topic and I feel it’s a major oversight on Newport’s part. He even says “The big picture point worth noting here, however, is that these disqualifying traits still have nothing to do with whether a job is the right fit for some innate passion. They remain much more general. Working right, therefore, still trumps finding the right work.” While I’m convinced of Cal’s Career Capital theory, I’m also convinced it can’t be applied to any job and think this section deserves more attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;becoming-a-craftsman&quot;&gt;Becoming a Craftsman&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of deliberate practice is a very interesting concept to me. I think it’s probably because so few people engage in the practice that no one speaks on the topic with authority. The basic premise is this: focus on difficult activities specifically chosen to stretch your abilities where they most need stretching and getting feedback on those activities. The term was coined by Anders Ericsson in the early 1990’s. Ericsson describes it this way: an activity designed, typically by a teacher, for the sole purpose of effectively improving specific aspects of an individual’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In careers with competitive structures such as athletics, chess, and even music, deliberate practice is common enough to have books written on the topic and common paths to follow. But what if you’re a knowledge worker, or in a field without a clear training philosophy? Newport profiles two people, both knowledge workers, who used the technique. Alex Berger used deliberate practice to become a writer and producer of cable TV shows and Mike Jackson used it to become an entrepreneur and investor in the renewable energy market. What’s interesting is how they employed deliberate practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex Berger’s exercise of this practice was about what you’d expect. Being a writer he was able to write and get feedback on the writing. He then paired that with instructional books on storytelling and screenwriting. Mike Jackson didn’t have much of a “deliverable” that could be reviewed so he decided to track his time on a spreadsheet. His goal with the spreadsheet was to become more intentional about his workday. By tracking his time he was able to ensure that he didn’t spend all day on email or something else that wouldn’t make him better at what he does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex and Mike’s stories provide a nice example of deliberate practice for knowledge workers but how can we apply it to our own work? According to Newport, there are two types of career capital markets: winner-take-all and auction. “The first task in building a deliberate practice strategy is to figure out what type of career capital market you are competing in. Answering this question might seem obvious, but it’s surprisingly easy to get it wrong.” Unfortunately, there’s little elaboration on this point. There are a few examples from Alex and Mike’s stories but, since it’s so “easy to get wrong,” there should probably be a checklist of some type. Sadly there isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section seems a little thin to me. The only thing that’s really said on the matter is that you need to &lt;em&gt;get good&lt;/em&gt; by pushing yourself in tasks related to your career that stretch you. Pushing passed what’s comfortable and also getting feedback. According to Newport, “it’s in honest, sometimes harsh feedback that you learn where to retrain your focus in order to continue to make progress.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rule-3-control-traps-and-how-to-avoid-them&quot;&gt;Rule #3: Control Traps and How to Avoid Them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control, according to Newport, is one of the most powerful traits you can acquire when creating work you love but there are traps you need to be aware of in acquiring it. Cal tells of people who traded their career capital for control and others who tried to gain control without any capital. If you can’t already guess, the people who had yet to build capital in their careers didn’t fare so well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more interesting part of this section is where Cal talks about how to avoid the “control traps.” Newport talks with Derek Sivers whose “whole career has been about making big moves, often in the face of resistance, to gain more control over what he does and how he does it.” So what criteria does Sivers use to decide which projects to pursue and which to abandon? “I have this principle about money that overrides my other life rules,” says Sivers, “[d]o what people are willing to pay for.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling to raise money for an idea, or are thinking that you will support your idea with unrelated work, then you need to rethink the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal liked Derek’s idea so much he decided to give it a name: The Law of Financial Viability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When deciding whether to follow an appealing pursuit that will introduce more control into your work life, seek evidence of whether people are willing to pay for it. If you find this evidence, continue. If not, move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rule4-think-small-act-big-or-the-importance-of-mission&quot;&gt;Rule#4: Think Small, Act Big (Or, the Importance of Mission)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;missions-require-capital&quot;&gt;Missions Require Capital&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport talks about how having a mission is a “crucial factor in loving what you do.” “To have a mission is to have a unifying focus for your career. It’s more general than a specific job and can span multiple positions. It provides an answer to the question, What should I do with my life?” But then he says “[a] mission launched without [career capital] is likely doomed to sputter and die.” So what then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal gives three accounts of people who have stated missions. The first started without career capital and failed at fulfilling the stated mission. The next had no career capital and failed at even defining a mission. The other, while developing career capital, was able to define a mission and has become successful in the process. In explaining these different results, Newport offers: “A good career mission is similar to a scientific breakthrough—it’s an innovation waiting to be discovered in the adjacent possible of your field. If you want to identify a mission for your working life, therefore, you must first get to the cutting edge—the only place where these missions become visible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In hindsight, these observations are obvious. If life-transforming missions could be found with just a little navel-gazing and an optimistic attitude, changing the world would be commonplace. But it’s not commonplace; it’s instead quite rare. This rareness, we now understand, is because these breakthroughs require that you first get to the cutting edge, and this is hard—the type of hardness that most of us try to avoid in our working lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;missions-require-little-bets&quot;&gt;Missions Require Little Bets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So once you’ve built some career capital how do you determine a mission? Newport talks about a system of “little bets” to give you an idea of where your interests lie and also to see if anyone else is interested in the idea. Cal profiles Kirk French an Archaeologist and host of The Discovery Channel’s &lt;em&gt;American Treasures&lt;/em&gt;. Some of the “little bets” that French explored were: starting a music festival, managing a hotel, recording two CD’s, digitizing the 16mm film of an ecological documentary and filming a new version of the documentary which required trips to Mexico. Then French, feeling a strong urge to bring archeology to the public, decided to start following up on calls people made to the archeology department at Penn State where he was working. He decided to visit people when they claimed to have found a dinosaur footprint or some artifact—and not only visit but film the visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kirk’s mission was to popularize archaeology, and he wanted to do so in a way that generated an exciting life. Hosting &lt;em&gt;American Treasures&lt;/em&gt; made this mission a reality. The question at hand is how he made this leap from a general idea to specific action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing to note is the little steps taken in getting to the TV deal. French didn’t try to predetermine a mission and stick to it no matter what. He tried things that would only last a few months, got feedback and tried something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;missions-require-marketing&quot;&gt;Missions Require Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport profiles how a few people used marketing principles to launch projects into missions. It’s not a concept that many career advice books cover and not something I thought an academic would have given much credence—kudos to Cal for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic idea of using marketing is to promote your little bets and see which one’s gain traction. If no one seems interested, move on. If, however, your projects start getting a lot of attention, it might be something to pour gas on. Cal sums it this way: By using little bets and the law of remarkability, you greatly increase your chances of finding ways to transform your mission from a compelling idea into a compelling career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a surprising change of heart reading this book. At first, I was against the notion that passion can’t be predetermined. It seemed reasonable that I could determine which jobs I wouldn’t like and, therefore, determine jobs that I would like. By the second half of the book Cal had built a pretty solid argument and, although there were parts I think he should have spent more time on, he converted me to a Career Capitalist. One of the parts he should have spent more time on is finding the original field to pursue. How do I know what field in which to start building career capital?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple stories in the book, most notably Steve Jobs and Pardis Sabeti, that underscore how important it is to be open to the options available to you—to not jump into one field with both feet and close all other doors. If Newport is correct, and I believe he is, you’ll need to pick something and stick with it but the lessons of the people profiled seem to be, don’t jump too early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal talks about a three-level pyramid in the section on developing your mission. After reading how he uses it, it occurred to me that the pyramid could be used twice. The first time around would be to determine which general field to pursue. The bottom of the pyramid is where you would read and research all fields you’re interested in. The middle would be the projects or little bets where you try different things to see if something sticks or is especially interesting. The top would be the general field you decide to pursue. Then once you had settled on a field you start over using the bottom as background research on general interests in the field you’ve chosen. The middle is to explore projects based on the reading and research done at the bottom level and see what sticks. Once something does stick you could articulate a mission at the top level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing of the book leaves much to be desired. It reads like an academic text instead of how you’d expect popular non-fiction to read. Newport repeats himself a lot, as if he were writing a textbook. I found myself, more than once, saying in frustration “you said that already!” With that said, this is a great book and a great argument against the follow your passion message that everyone else preaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reading List — June 2013</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a fan of Chris Anderson’s &lt;em&gt;Long Tail&lt;/em&gt; and when I heard he had a new book on the “long tail of atoms,” I wanted to take a look. In his new book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/makers/oclc/941367656&quot;&gt;Makers&lt;/a&gt; he explores the world of 3D publishing and how this maker movement is likely to create a lot of disruption in the manufacturing industry—especially for smaller companies. He talks about how small, custom, manufacturing jobs that would have been sent to China, will likely be produced closer to the distribution points in the very near future. If you’re interested in DIY this book is a good read, if you’re in the manufacturing industry it’s a must read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom was in town for a visit this month and we were talking about a new job she was looking to get. The conversation was centered around starting a blog and building some community to gain mindshare. Even though I’d never read it myself I recommended Seth Godin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/tribes-we-need-you-to-lead-us/oclc/1043911290&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tribes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Since it was on my list anyway and so many people have recommended it, I decided it was a perfect time for me to read it also. Seth didn’t disappoint. If you’re looking to build a community online Seth gives the philosophical background—and permission—you need to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was browsing Mitch Joel’s site recently when I found a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twistimage.com/blog/archives/dear-seth-godin/&quot;&gt;“fan letter” he’d written to Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;. At the end of the letter he mentioned that the idea for this fan letter had come from Austin Kleon’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/steal-like-an-artist-10-things-nobody-told-you-about-being-creative/oclc/824175708&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steal Like an Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The book has popped onto my radar a couple other times lately, so I decided to check it out. I’m glad I did. I might put this book on the yearly reading list with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/war-of-art-break-through-the-blocks-and-win-your-inner-creative-battles/oclc/955664049&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The War of Art&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re having trouble getting started with creative projects, this might give you the kick in the paints you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only other book I finished this month was Edward de Bono’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/six-thinking-hats/oclc/973272311&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Six Thinking Hats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but I mostly skimmed it. In it de Bono discusses how getting groups of people to thinking in certain ways at certain time can speed decisions. For example, if someone is badgering an idea, you can tell them that this great “black hat” thinking and have them switch to some other hat. This get’s them thinking about the idea from different angles without embarrassing them by saying something like “stop being so negative.” It’s a good concept but I think the book is about 100 pages too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-articles&quot;&gt;Web Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of articles on the web. I’ve got around 100 RSS feeds in Feedly. Then there’s articles on Facebook, LinkedIn, Google+ and Twitter. All the ones that look interesting get pushed to Instapaper and downloaded to my Kindle. Of those hundreds of articles, here are seven I found this month that are worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://searchenginewatch.com/article/2271733/How-to-Focus-Amplify-Your-Personal-Brand&quot;&gt;How to Focus &amp;amp; Amplify Your Personal Brand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ailiangan.com/post/51934892087/before-seth-godin-was-seth-godin&quot;&gt;Before Seth Godin was Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jetsetcitizen.com/personal-development/good-human/&quot;&gt;What does it mean to be a Good Human?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2010/11/05/ancient-rivers-of-money/&quot;&gt;Ancient Rivers of Money&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130619133031-7668018-ultimate-cheat-sheet-on-super-connecting&quot;&gt;Ultimate ‘Cheat Sheet’ on Super-Connecting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tropicalmba.com/questions-and-answers-for-location-independent-entrepreneurs/&quot;&gt;Questions and Answers For Location Independent Entrepreneurs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tomtunguz.com/price-discovery&quot;&gt;The Most Effective Price Discovery Question for Your Company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-june-2013/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-june-2013/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Reading List — March, April and May 2013</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was WWOOFing in Japan I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/millionaire-messenger/oclc/944463750&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Millionaire Messenger&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Brendon Burchard. This was a great read and gave some great insights into the “guru industry.” If you have no interest in the industry but want to be an author, this book gives good advice on building a platform. Most of the book is based on his experience becoming well known in this guru industry. And there are some candid moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I followed in the footsteps of those who had come before me, those who had left a real job to go out and follow their dreams and share their important message with the world. And I got the same results as most of them: I promptly went broke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave up on Seth Godin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/icarus-deception-how-high-will-you-fly/oclc/922295414&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Icarus Deception&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—I might have made it halfway. I really like hearing Seth speak and he has written some great books, but it’s been a few years. His last few efforts have read like blog posts strung together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Seth, what’s great on the web is not great in a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MJ DeMarco’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/millionaire-fastlane-crack-the-code-to-wealth-and-live-rich-for-a-lifetime/oclc/1099537824&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Millionaire Fastlane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was a surprisingly good read. I kept hearing how good it was but had no interest because of the title. This book delivered. I highly recommend it if you’re thinking of entrepreneurship, especially web based entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had started Masanobu’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/one-straw-revolution-an-introduction-to-natural-farming/oclc/991592787&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The One-Straw Revolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a year or so before but never finished it. Living in Bangkok it was hard to imagine the fields and farming he was talking about. Ever since I heard about his philosophy of “do nothing farming” I wanted to know more. Unfortunately this book is more of an overview than I was hoping and by the end it was getting a bit political. If you’re interested in alternative methods of agriculture or alternative methods of thinking, it’s a short read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having enjoyed Malcolm Gladwell’s &lt;em&gt;Outliers&lt;/em&gt; I thought I’d try &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/what-the-dog-saw-and-other-adventures/oclc/960691099&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What the Dog Saw&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I knew it was a compilation of stories he’d written for &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt; and since I like his writing style I thought the book would be good. And it was, but not good enough for me to see it through to the end. I gave up about half way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to get back to some marketing related reading just before returning to Thailand and read Al Ries and Jack Trout’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/positioning-the-battle-for-your-mind/oclc/986516462&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Positioning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This was a great read. In fact, I’ve never read anything from them I didn’t like. They covered many points on how to position a company, product or person and gave a lot of case studies to back up their points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-articles&quot;&gt;Web Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyblogger has started a new feature called The Writer Files. They profile writers and ask a lot of “how do you do what you do” type questions. Recently they interviewed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.copyblogger.com/how-austin-kleon-writes/&quot;&gt;Austin Kleon&lt;/a&gt; and I thought his profile was interesting. Especially the part where he said he hates writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What I really like to do is read. Writing lets me be a professional reader, so I do as little of it as I can get away with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of talk about how the web makes people less productive and doesn’t allow for good, human, connection. Some people avoid online social networks for this very reason. Paul Miller thought this and decided to try going offline for one year to see if he’d become more productive and form better relationships. In his article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2013/5/1/4279674/im-still-here-back-online-after-a-year-without-the-internet&quot;&gt;“I’m still here: back online after a year without the internet”&lt;/a&gt;, he says it wasn’t the life changing experience he thought it was going to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first learned about Dr Brown’s “Listening Approach” it was obvious to me why language classes were failing people. Recently I was looking to explain what the method was about and, not wanting to write what had already been written, I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://effortlessacquisition.blogspot.com/2004/06/silent-period-teaching-methods.html&quot;&gt;Silent Period Teaching Methods&lt;/a&gt; by AJ Hoge and Silent Period Hypothesis by Taeko Tomioka, both of which I liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I spent many months trying to start an English school based on Dr Brown’s method and really wish I’d have read &lt;a href=&quot;http://avichal.wordpress.com/2011/10/07/why-education-startups-do-not-succeed/&quot;&gt;Why Education Startups Do Not Succeed&lt;/a&gt; before spending all that energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in Japan I was speaking to another WWOOFer about Jim Rogers’s predictions about how farmers will be millionaires in the future and not bankers. While I was searching the web for some examples of things trending this way I found that Southeast Asia’s economy is predicted to grow 5.9% this year. A lot of this is due to Japanese companies looking to move their manufacturing operations out of China. (The article has since be deleted.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of Cal Newport. Sometimes his articles resonate with me and sometimes they don’t but I’m still a fan. In fact I wish I could be more like him. Knowing he might alienate people he still publishes his ideas. Recently he wrote “&lt;a href=&quot;http://calnewport.com/blog/2013/04/03/you-can-be-busy-or-remarkable-but-not-both/&quot;&gt;You Can Be Busy or Remarkable — But Not Both&lt;/a&gt;”. A very interesting concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in driving web traffic there was an article on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.bufferapp.com/social-media-metrics-improve&quot;&gt;measuring and improving your social media efforts&lt;/a&gt; on the Buffer Blog. It’s one of the best articles I’ve read on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-spring-2013/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/reading-list-spring-2013/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Never Eat Alone — Book Review</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Keith Ferrazzi has built one of the world’s largest networks and considering where he came from, that’s a feat. His book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/never-eat-alone-and-other-secrets-to-success-one-relationship-at-a-time/oclc/960953034&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Never Eat Alone: And Other Secrets to Success, One Relationship at a Time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, details how he built his network and how you replicate his process if you want to build a network of your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mind-set&quot;&gt;The Mind-Set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book opens with a story of Keith employed as a caddie in a wealthy town adjacent to his boyhood home. During this time carrying clubs, he watched as the country club members found each other jobs, invested time and money in one another’s ideas and helped each other’s kids get into the best schools, get the best internships and the best jobs. “Before my eyes, I saw proof that success breeds success and, indeed, the rich &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; get richer,” says Ferrazzi. “Poverty, I realized, wasn’t only a lack of financial resources; it was isolation from the kind of people that could help you make more of yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To achieve your goals in life,” Ferrazzi realized, “it matters less how smart you are, how much innate talent you’re born with, or even, most eye-opening to me, where you came from and how much you started out with.” What matters most is realizing, you can’t get there alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing his story of working as a caddie, Ferrazzi learns that what he thought of as networking was, instead, connecting—sharing knowledge and resources, time and energy, friends and associates—in an effort to provide value to others. He notes, “[w]hat I saw on the golf course—friends helping friends and families helping families they cared about—had nothing to do with manipulation or quid pro quo. Rarely was there any running tally of who did what for whom, or strategies concocted in which you give just so you could get.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first section of the book is mostly about Keith’s upbringing and how he came to some of the conclusions he has about networking. He talks about his father’s gutsy move to ask the CEO of his steel-mill if he could help Keith get into a private school. How being around successful people—simply knowing them—gave him access to people and places he wouldn’t have had otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-skill-set&quot;&gt;The Skill Set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first section, Ferrazzi talks about why you’d want to build a network and in this section how to do it. Sections two and three I found to be the most interesting and helpful. If you’ve decided to read a book on networking you probably don’t need to be told why it’s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things Keith talks about I would never have thought of myself. He talks about doing research on people you wish to meet who will be attending the same conferences as you. By knowing what their business does, how their business is doing and even some personal stuff about the person, you’ll be ready to make small talk that they will want to engage in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferrazzi gives a few other tips for conferences, such as, help the organizer. By helping organize the event you’ll know who’s coming and when you see a name you want to meet, the organizer will probably introduce you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking at an event will also help. I realized this months ago when I spoke on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bradonomics.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/tips-for-a-better-barcamp/&quot;&gt;language learning at Barcamp Bangkok&lt;/a&gt;. People see you as an expert and will come to you after the talk to discuss details or exchange contact info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connecting-with-connectors&quot;&gt;Connecting with Connectors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read a lot of networking advice on the web and most people are saying the same things. Every article has only slight variations to the hundred other articles on networking. Ferrazzi has a couple chapters in his book that covers things I’ve never read elsewhere. This chapter on connecting with people who already have large networks is something I’ve never read before. And while I intuitively understand the idea, I’d never thought about who are these “super-connectors,” and where can I find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith lists seven types people who typically have large networks—restaurateurs, headhunters, lobbyists, fundraisers, public relations people, politicians and journalists—and gives advice on why and how to connect with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-art-of-small-talk&quot;&gt;The Art of Small Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we get to the part I have the most trouble with—the approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point in the book Keith says “[f]or many people, the fear of meeting others is closely tied to the fear of public speaking.” If you have a problem with public speaking, then a group like ToastMasters will help. But what about someone like me? I have no problems giving talks to groups, if I’m expected to be there, speaking to the group is no problem, even enjoyable. My problem is walking up to that one guy at a networking event and saying “hi, my name is Brad.” I was hopeful this chapter would give me some techniques or tactics to soften the pain—it didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing offering any comfort at all was when Keith said, “[y]ou’re never going to be completely ready to meet new people; there is no perfect moment. Your fears will never be completely quieted because inviting rejection is never going to be appealing.” Knowing that it’s difficult for everyone, even someone like Ferrazzi, makes me feel a little better …I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-anchor-tenants-and-feed-them&quot;&gt;Find Anchor Tenants and Feed Them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting concept, throwing dinner parties to connect different parts of your network or to invite friends-of-friends to become better acquainted.  But there was a disconnect during the first part of the chapter when Keith was talking about the parties he has at his place in Los Angeles. When he mentioned people adjourning to the living room where there was live piano music, made me think &lt;em&gt;I’m years, if not decades, from doing something like this&lt;/em&gt;. Thankfully he didn’t end there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferrazzi talks about how he got started throwing dinner parties in college; “[i]n those early years, my 400-square-foot, one bedroom apartment … with a kitchen table that could barely seat two adults, held wild get-togethers for four, six, even fifteen guests.” He goes on to talk about having your parties catered or cooking something the day before—something that will keep like chilly—and supplementing it with lots of wine. Most intriguing was how he gets interesting people to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anchor tenant concept is where you find someone—a friend of a friend—who’s one rung up the social latter from you and your peer group. That anchor allows you to reach beyond your circle in subsequent invitations and pull people who wouldn’t otherwise attend. “To put it in terms of the company cafeteria, now that you have the CEO eating lunch at the manager’s table, other executives will jump at the opportunity to eat at the table, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of the better chapters in the book and I’ve been planning dinner parties in my head since reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/never-eat-alone-and-other-secrets-to-success-one-relationship-at-a-time/oclc/960953034&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Never Eat Alone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was a great book. As with all books, there were parts that went a little long and parts that were short where I wish he would elaborate. The chapters about connecting with connectors and having dinner parties where some of the best lessons in the book and something new for me. After reading the book, I realize the best way to quiet my introverted tendencies is to have people come to me …now I’ve just got to find ways to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/never-eat-alone-book-review/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/never-eat-alone-book-review/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Ultimate Sales Letter — Book Review</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I looked for other reviews on this book before writing my own and was surprised to find so many positive reviews on other blogs. I couldn’t find a negative review on the first few pages of Google results. And while I didn’t hate the book, I had a feeling the whole time that I was being setup for something else. It felt like those “free” seminars where they sell books, CD’s or training courses at the back of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more appropriate title might be &lt;em&gt;The Ultimate Overview&lt;/em&gt;. While this is a good introduction to the Kennedy System of writing sales letters, it’s just that, an introduction. But even though it was an overview there is still some insight to be gained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/ultimate-sales-letter/oclc/1051453103&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ultimate Sales Letter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, written by Dan Kennedy, is “organized” into parts, chapters, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; steps. I’ve used a modified version of the steps to guide this summary, as the parts and chapters make no sense to me and confuse the organization of the material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-into-the-customer&quot;&gt;Get “Into” the Customer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advice in this step is more for professional copywriters. Probably you are very aware of what your customers are into, what magazines they read, what websites they visit, what industry events they attend, etc. But, if for some reason, you don’t know much about your customers, this step has an example of a marketer writing for the dental industry that could give you some ideas to better understand your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-into-the-offer&quot;&gt;Get “Into” the Offer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since “[p]eople do not buy things for what they are; they buy things for what they do[,]” Dan recommends writing a list of features and benefits on 3x5 cards so you can reference and arrange when writing your letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also talks, in this step, about the “the hidden benefit.” At a conference for life insurance salesmen on methods of recruiting agents, the organizer overheard many conversations about playing golf between sessions. He realized the ultimate goal of recruiting agents to their organization was to allow them more time on the golf course. When advertising for the next conference he addressed this directly with a letter titled: “Puts Recruiting on Autopilot So You Can Go Play Golf!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you write the features of your offer, think about the benefit each feature provides and focus on that. Your prospect doesn’t care about how many BTU’s your heater produces, they care if it will keep them warm, so address this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-damaging-admission-and-address-flaws-openly&quot;&gt;Create a Damaging Admission and Address Flaws Openly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every product, service, and offer has some unattractive points. Nothing’s perfect, and everybody knows that. By admitting and openly discussing the drawbacks to your offer, your “credibility stock” goes way up on most of your letter recipients’ charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;posted-sales-letters&quot;&gt;Posted Sales Letters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kennedy goes on for a while about posted letters, or snail mail. He talks at the end of the book about web based sales letters and why they’re more difficult than posted sales letters. It seems strange to me that he wouldn’t have talked about this first, especially in the 2011 edition. There are advantages and disadvantages to both methods of delivery, but it would seem that Dan believes there is no advantage to web based sales letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to gloss over this section. Just know if you intend to send mail via the post, there are things you’ll need to consider such as the look of the envelop and whether it’s metered or stamped … in general you want it to look as much like a personal letter as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;presenting-price-in-a-sales-letter&quot;&gt;Presenting Price in a Sales Letter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section, oddly titled “Beat the Bugaboo,” talks about focusing on the volume and value of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of volume, or “bulk” as Kennedy calls it, is given for how to sell an apple. “[I]f we were writing a sales letter for an ordinary apple, instead of just saying that “an apple a day keeps the doctor away,” we might list every vitamin and mineral provided by the apple, then list every health benefit delivered by each of those vitamins and minerals. We might then show the huge bulk of other foods you’d have to consume to get those same nutrients and benefits—all to turn that little apple into a huge “bulk” of benefits and value.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use physical weight in your description of the product as people equate value with bulk. Look at what Seth Godin did with the 19-pound book in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/297519465/the-icarus-deception-why-make-art-new-from-seth-go&quot;&gt;Kickstarter campaign&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;The Icarus Deception&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kennedy also talks about discussing the price you paid to develop the product by telling the story of how it was created and tested before bringing it to market. Or talking about how the price of the parts is worth more than the whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final advice on pricing is the “3 easy payments” method you’ve probably seen on infomercials. He talks about how in one case there was no difference in sales generated with price points at $39.95, 2 payments of $19.95 or 3 payments of $19.95.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing--editing&quot;&gt;Writing &amp;amp; Editing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan spends a couple steps on the writing and editing process. If you’ve ever read any of his sales letters, you’ll know the style. Short sentences, redundancy, 2 or 3 post scripts, yellow highlighting. He claims this style sells product and, while I’m sure they’ve tested it, I can’t bring myself to write like this. If it was under a pen name, perhaps…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He addresses this skepticism directly saying copywriters might think they are writing to a more educated or sophisticated crowd but his style sells more even with this audience. He then gives a few pages to validate his claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;editing--testing&quot;&gt;Editing &amp;amp; Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last third of the book is dedicated to how important editing and testing are in getting the perfect sales letter. A/B testing a sales letter online or via email is easy enough but if you intend to send posted letters, Dan gives a few ways to test your letters before paying for postage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m leaving this part of the review a bit thin as it wasn’t particularly interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things Kennedy glosses over that I wish he’d have spent more time on. Things like answering objections and serial letters. And things, like editing, I wish he’d have spent less time on. I wouldn’t recommend the book unless you can get it from the library. It might be $10, but that’s $10 you can spend on a book that teaches how to write sales letters and one that isn’t a sales letter itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking his book &lt;em&gt;No B.S. Direct Marketing&lt;/em&gt; would have the real meat I was looking for I checked the Amazon reviews. He is criticized multiple times for up-selling in that book also. I don’t know where to get the whole Kennedy system but it doesn’t seem to be in his books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A note about format: if you’re interested enough to buy the book, get a physical copy. I read it on a Kindle and you can tell the book wasn’t made to be digitized. The formatting is off, some parts are hard to follow, there are quotes that didn’t format well for the Kindle edition and the sales letters are difficult to read. I’ve got to assume the physical edition doesn’t have these formatting problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/dan-kennedy-ultimate-sales-letter-review/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/dan-kennedy-ultimate-sales-letter-review/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Education of Millionaires — Book Summary</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I read an article by Michael Ellsberg called &lt;a href=&quot;https://tim.blog/2011/09/29/8-steps-to-getting-what-you-want-without-formal-credentials/&quot;&gt;8 Steps to Getting What You Want… Without Formal Credentials&lt;/a&gt; when it was first published in September of 2011. At the time, it didn’t have much affect on me. A few weeks ago a friend recommended the article and I read it again. This time, I was ready to hear Ellsberg’s message. The book reviews on bradonomics are largely from the advice he gives in that article so I thought it fitting to read and summarize his book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re already on the “college-isn’t-the-best-use-of-time” bandwagon, you can skip the book. It does have a lot of good stories about people finding their way without a university degree but the article above outlines the core of Michael’s approach to educating yourself without the sales pitch that university isn’t all it’s cracked-up to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/education-of-millionaires-its-not-what-you-think-and-its-not-too-late/oclc/760072931&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Education of Millionaires&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, is broken into seven success skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-1-how-to-make-your-work-meaningful-and-you-meaning-work&quot;&gt;Success Skill #1: How to Make Your Work Meaningful and You Meaning Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve read a lot of &lt;em&gt;follow your passion&lt;/em&gt; literature and never found much of it helpful. I’ve done exercises to learn what your passion is and read about how to turn that passion into a career. After every book and every article I’ve been left wanting. Perhaps it’s not the authors fault, it is a hard topic to write on, but I’m more-and-more persuaded that what Ellsberg talks about in this first success skill is the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael talks about “The Art of Earning a Living” and gives four steps to “aligning your money and your meaning.” The basic premise being, once you aren’t worried about paying your bills, you can create more time to focus on meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-getting-on-your-feet-financially&quot;&gt;Step 1: Getting on Your Feet Financially&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellsberg recommends getting on your feet financially before trying to pursue your art. “Get a square job, a corporate job, a temp job, a boring nine-to-five. Don’t feel anything is ‘beneath you’ so long as it pays … Give up your ‘art,’ ‘purpose,’ or ‘meaning’ for a little while and know what it means to be financially stable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Finding a comfortable meeting ground for your money and your meaning is going to require a lot of experimentation. Experimentation takes time. It takes money. And it takes room to fall and to fail.” It’s so much easier to make a difference in the world when your bills are covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-create-more-room-for-experimentation&quot;&gt;Step 2: Create More Room for Experimentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating time for experiments if you are working freelance should be easy. But if you’re working a full-time corporate job it will prove more difficult. In this case Ellsberg recommends seeing if you can move to a results focused, instead of an hours focused position and recommends some books to help make the transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/why-work-sucks-and-how-to-fix-it-the-results-only-revolution/oclc/644667441&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why Work Sucks and How to Fix It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Cali Ressler and Jody Thompson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chapter 12 of Tim Ferrisss’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/4-hour-workweek-escape-9-5-live-anywhere-and-join-the-new-rich/oclc/944072533&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Four-Hour Workweek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; titled “Disappearing Act: How to Escape the Office”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/custom-fit-workplace-choose-when-where-and-how-to-work-and-boost-your-bottom-line/oclc/526098198&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Custom-Fit Workplace&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Joan Blades and Nanette Fondas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-with-this-new-space-begin-experimenting&quot;&gt;Step 3: With This New Space, Begin Experimenting!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step is a bit of a let-down if you’re hoping to uncover your passion, should you not know it already. There’s no real advice on &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to experiment or what to look for when you try something. Probably a topic outside the scope of this book…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He does say “[m]any people are quite content to leave things here: they have a career that pays the bills and in which they’re increasingly making a difference and finding meaning, through exercising leadership. And they also have time during their day or week to pursue meaningful passions outside of work.” For these people, there’s no reason to move to step four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-striking-out-on-your-own&quot;&gt;Step 4: Striking Out on Your Own&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how “striking out on your own” looks for you, Ellsberg says “you’re going to have to do a deep dive into the success skills in this book, particularly marketing, sales, and networking.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking about what the steps are to “aligning your money and your meaning,” Ellsberg give a personal story about how he went from a “broke miserable wannabe” to a financially secure, professional author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-2-how-to-find-great-mentors-and-teachers-connect-with-powerful-and-influential-people-and-build-a-world-class-network&quot;&gt;Success Skill #2: How to Find Great Mentors and Teachers, Connect with Powerful and Influential People and Build a World-Class Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellsberg talks about using your “Connection Capital” to build your network. By introducing people when you don’t have the skills to help, you’ve made them a part of your network also. And this seems obvious enough, but how do you use your network to grow your network when you don’t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; a network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael recommends giving relevant and valuable advice. Even if you think you don’t have any advice to offer, you probably do. There are three areas that Eben Pagen, one of the interviewees in the book, says people spend most of their time worrying about. Money, relationships and health. Very few people have all three figured out and if you can uncover the one they need help with and give good advice, you’ll be able to bring them into your network. So how can you uncover their area of worry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m going to teach you two questions that, if you put them into use at parties, events, and conferences, will change your life forever and will grow your network faster than you ever thought possible:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What’s most exciting for you right now in your life/business?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What’s challenging for you in your life/business right now?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellsberg has given a few talks and written a few articles that can help expand on this topic if you like. The talk at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDmOgLabl_M&quot;&gt;Awesomeness Fest 2012&lt;/a&gt; was good, or if you’d rather read, this is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/michaelellsberg/2011/08/31/how-to-network-your-way-to-world-class-mentors-the-thiel-fellowship-lecture-part-1/&quot;&gt;transcript of the same talk&lt;/a&gt; given at a different event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-3-what-every-successful-person-needs-to-know-about-marketing-and-how-to-teach-yourself&quot;&gt;Success Skill #3: What Every Successful Person Needs to Know About Marketing, and How to Teach Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Ellsberg, marketing means direct-response copywriting and this chapter is dedicated to examples of why this is a good method of marketing to understand. According to Ellsberg the way to learn direct-response copywriting is to model those people who are already good at it. He recommends signing up to the email lists of the below marketers and studying their copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.copyblogger.com/&quot;&gt;Copyblogger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marieforleo.com/&quot;&gt;Marie Forleo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mattfurey.com/&quot;&gt;Matt Furey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jonathanfields.com/&quot;&gt;Jonathan Fields&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thegaryhalbertletter.com/&quot;&gt;Gary Halbert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketingbullets.com/&quot;&gt;Gary Bencivenga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dankennedy.com/&quot;&gt;Dan Kennedy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ebenpagan.com/&quot;&gt;Eben Pagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://frankkern.com/&quot;&gt;Frank Kern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pleasurableweightloss.com/&quot;&gt;Jena la Flamme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-4-what-every-successful-person-needs-to-know-about-sales-and-how-to-teach-yourself&quot;&gt;Success Skill #4: What Every Successful Person Needs to Know About Sales, and How to Teach Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellsberg spends the majority of this chapter writing about how sales isn’t taught in university and how this is a detriment to students. He finally gets around to saying, “[n]o single skill you could possibly learn correlates more directly with your real-world success than learning sales,” and recommends reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/833015.SPIN_Selling&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPIN Selling&lt;/em&gt; by Neil Rackham&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-5-how-to-invest-for-success&quot;&gt;Success Skill #5: How to Invest for Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter is largely about why college isn’t a good use of resources and how investing in your own earning power, a strategy Ellsberg calls &lt;em&gt;Bootstrapping Your Own Education and Success&lt;/em&gt;, is a better option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[B]ootstrapping,” Ellsburg writes, “is keeping expenses low, generating income right away and continually reinvesting as much of that income as effectively as possible into expanding your future income.” Unfortunately he doesn’t give much advice on how to accomplish this “reinvesting.” There are a few stories about how others built businesses or got jobs based on developing skills, but overall the task left to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-6-build-the-brand-of-you&quot;&gt;Success Skill #6: Build the Brand of You&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter is about reputation. Ellsberg says personal branding can be summed in one sentence: “Your brand is what people think about when they hear your name.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If people think ‘trustworthy, confident, intelligent, funny, hip, savvy, and up-and-coming’ when they hear your name, then that is your brand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If people think ‘wannabe loser’ when they hear your name, then that is your brand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And if people think absolutely nothing when they hear your name, then you have no brand.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seth Godin wrote a blog post called &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2008/03/why-bother-havi.html&quot;&gt;Why bother having a resume?&lt;/a&gt; where he said, “[g]reat jobs, world class jobs, jobs people kill for… those jobs don’t get filled by people emailing in resumes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re buying this idea and believe that building a personal brand is the way to go, or that it will help what you’re already doing, Michael has a few stories in this chapter to give you a better understanding of how this has worked for other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;success-skill-7-the-entrepreneurial-mind-set-versus-the-employee-mind-set&quot;&gt;Success Skill #7: The Entrepreneurial Mind-set Versus the Employee Mind-set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is a bit hard to pin-down without rewriting large parts of the book. The basic concept is that your average entrepreneur thinks different than your average employee, and this difference in mindset is worth noticing and worth changing, assuming you don’t already possess it. And according to Ellsberg it doesn’t matter if you intend to be an entrepreneur or not, having an entrepreneurial mindset is beneficial even for employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;epilogue&quot;&gt;Epilogue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The epilogue is more stories about how going into debt for college is a bad idea. It’s probably best to skip this section unless you’re a high school student looking to harden your argument with your parents for why you don’t want to go to university. But if there’s one part of the book that really sums the idea that going to college isn’t a good idea, I think it’s this part from chapter 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve got an investment opportunity for you. It’s going to require an investment of about $45,000 to $200,000 on your part over several years. Given your current finances, you’re going to need to borrow a large part of that amount, that is, invest on margin, but that’s OK, the rates are pretty low.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The business I’d like you to invest in is, well, sort of in the exploratory/development phase. It doesn’t really know what business it’s in, to be frank, or what product or service it sells. In fact, it may not even know that for a few years. The chief executive in the business may have to move back in with her parents at some point during this time—before she figures out the business’s mission, revenue model, or core competency.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The business you’re about to invest in has absolutely no knowledge or experience in sales or marketing. It doesn’t even really know how to keep its own books or balance a budget, and often runs up a lot of credit card debt. It’s not even sure it wants to be a business; the CEO may want to start a nonprofit, pursue a passion in acting, or go help orphans in Botswana. The chief executive has no business network or contacts to speak of, and in fact has no experience whatsoever running a business.
Wanna invest?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/education-of-millionaires-summary/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/education-of-millionaires-summary/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Trust Me I&apos;m Lying — Book Summary</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ryan Holiday works as the Director of Marketing at American Apparel. While working at American Apparel is his day job, he also advises many bestselling authors and multi-platinum musicians, people like Tucker Max and Robert Greene, in the art of media manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holiday has written a new book titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldcat.org/title/trust-me-im-lying-the-tactics-and-confessions-of-a-media-manipulator/oclc/1110760576&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trust Me I’m Lying: Confessions of a Media Manipulator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The book is split into two sections, the first about how Ryan exploits the media—blogs in particular—to get press and the second, a more detailed view of these exploitations and his change of heart in using these tactics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a basic understanding of how Holiday exploits the media, think of a chain where each link represents a media outlet. At the top are BBC and CNN and the bottom are bloggers for local websites. Ryan starts at the bottom with the bloggers who will do little fact-checking and once the story has run there, he calls the next media outlet up the chain. In a process he calls “iterative journalism” each subsequent contact assumes that since it’s run on the other sites it must be true and verified, so they also run the story without fact-checking. Using this process he’s able to create a lot of buzz, even in national publications, for his clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of this type of exploitation was when Holiday was promoting a movie for Tucker Max. Ryan went in the middle of the night to vandalize a billboard advertising the moving—that Ryan and Tucker paid for—to make it look like someone was angry about the movie’s release. Ryan took pictures of his own vandalism and sent them to a local blogger using a fake email. The blogger ran the story and Holiday started his process of moving the story up the chain until it was on national TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t assume this type of manipulation only works with people like Tucker Max. The same scam works whether the end goal is to sell books or to get donations for a charity. In one case Holiday advised a charity to create a video exaggerating the elements of the charities work. An article was then written for a small blog in Brooklyn with the video embedded. A little while later the Huffington Post picked up the article and an email was sent to a CBS reporter in Los Angeles who ran it on TV using clips from the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying problem—the reason the media is so easily manipulated—is the news-blog business model. Since blogs make their money from advertisements and ads are bought on an impression basis, blog owners are only concerned with pageviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revenue = Advertising x Traffic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Publishers and Advertisers can’t differentiate between the types of impressions an ad does on a site. So long as the page loads and the ads are seen, both sides are fulfilling their purpose. A click is a click.” “Knowing this, blogs do everything they can to increase [traffic]. Every decision a publisher makes is ruled by one dictum: &lt;em&gt;traffic by any means&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holiday goes through a series of tactics describing how he accomplished his PR and media storms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-1-bloggers-are-poor-help-pay-their-bills&quot;&gt;Tactic #1: Bloggers Are Poor; Help Pay Their Bills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan talks in this first tactic about how hard it is for bloggers to make any real money and knowing this, uses it against them. &lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;, run by Henry Blodget, says “[a]n employee making $60,000 a year needs to produce 1.8 million pageviews a month, every month, or they’re out.” And since 1.8 million pageviews is really, really hard, these bloggers are all too willing to take freebies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the exploitative loopholes here, I’m sure. So how do bloggers make any &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; money—a livable wage? The easiest way is to build a name for themselves and sell that name. “Once a blogger builds a personal brand—through scoops of controversy or major stories—they can expect a cushy job at a magazine or start-up desperate for the credibility and buzz that these attributes offer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan then goes through a few examples of people who’ve done exactly this, a &lt;em&gt;CNET&lt;/em&gt; blogger who got a job at Google or the &lt;em&gt;Wonkette&lt;/em&gt; editor who got jobs at Time.com, MSNBC, and Playboy. Holiday then suggests that if you want these journalists to write about you, you need to get to them before they’re famous. “For my part, I’ve lost track of the bloggers whose names I have helped make by giving them big stories (favorable and to my liking) and watched transition into bigger gigs at magazines, newspapers, and editorships at major blogs. In fact, the other day I was driving in Los Angeles and noticed a billboard on La Cienega Boulevard with nothing but a large face on it: the face of a video blogger who I’d started giving free clothes to back when his videos did a few thousand views apiece. Now his videos do millions of views, and he has a show on HBO. If you invest early in a blogger, you can buy your influence very cheaply.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-2-tell-them-what-they-want-to-hear&quot;&gt;Tactic #2: Tell Them What They Want to Hear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tactic can best be summed with this: &lt;em&gt;The Deliberate Leak&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Once during a lawsuit I needed to get some information into the public discussion of it, so I dashed off a fake internal memo, printed it out, scanned it, and sent the file to a bunch of blogs as if I were an employee leaking a “memo we’d just gotten from our boss.” The same bloggers who were uninterested in the facts when I informed them directly gladly put up EXCLUSIVE! and LEAKED! posts about it. They could tell my side of the story because I told it to them in words they wanted to hear. More people saw it than ever would have had I issued an “official statement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holiday then goes on to talk about how Press Releases can be used word-for-word in articles written on news blogs and how Wikipedia can be used to exaggerate the truth and then, once a blogger writes about it, citation added to create a “new truth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-3-give-them-what-spreads-not-whats-good&quot;&gt;Tactic #3: Give Them What Spreads, Not What’s Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tactic Holiday talks, mostly, about two sets of Detroit photographs. One of decaying, abandoned buildings—iconic buildings like the United Arts Theater and Michigan Central Station—and the other of foreclosed houses and their haggard residents. The set of photos without people spread while the set with people and animals didn’t and Ryan spends the chapter talking about why this happened and how it can be used by media manipulators to get their messages to spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-4-help-them-trick-their-readers&quot;&gt;Tactic #4: Help Them Trick Their Readers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, Ryan talks about how, in the hunt for pageviews, blog owners will go to great lengths to get their articles clicks and even greater lengths to get comments. “The best way to get online coverage is to tee a blogger up with a story that will obviously generate comments (or votes, or shares, or whatever). This impossible maze of pageviews [generated in the sign-up process] is so lucrative that bloggers can’t help but try to lure readers into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building on what he talked about in the last chapter with getting people emotionally evolved enough to bump pageviews, he had this to say about getting his articles noticed by journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I want Gawker or other blogs to write about my clients I intentionally exploit their ambivalence about deceiving people. If I am giving them an official comment on behalf of a client, I leave room for them to speculate by not fully addressing the issue. If I am creating the story as a fake tipster, I ask a lot of rhetorical questions: Could [some preposterous misreading of the situation] be what’s going on? Do you think that [juicy scandal] is what they’re hiding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-5-sell-them-something-they-can-sell-exploit-the-one-off-problem&quot;&gt;Tactic #5: Sell Them Something They Can Sell (Exploit The One-Off Problem)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Holiday, he got a lot of inspiration for the tactics he uses “by reading books like &lt;em&gt;The Harder They Fall&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;All the King’s Men&lt;/em&gt;, which are about press agents and media fixers for powerful politicians and criminals of many years ago.” Along with these books, he took case studies of the Yellow Press of the mid-to-late 1800’s. “You want to know how to con bloggers today? Look at media hoaxes from before your grandparents were born. The same things will play. They may even play better now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online publishers know “[p]eople don’t read one blog[,] [t]hey read a constant assortment of many blogs, and so there is little incentive to build trust.” Holiday knows that publishers know this, so when he sends his tips or “leaks,” he makes sure to include some type of sensationalism, extremism, sex, scandal or hatred and plays on the one-off nature of how news is read online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-6-make-it-all-about-the-headline&quot;&gt;Tactic #6: Make It All About The Headline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For Media that lives and dies by clicks it all comes down to the headline. It’s what catches the attention of the public—yelled by a newsboy or seen on a search engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you’re reading this review on a blog it should be no surprise to you that headlines are important online. It’s unlikely you found this on Google News, but let’s use that platform as an example. Google News displays twenty or so news stories. You may read one article, or you may read five, but it’s unlikely you’ll read them all, so each one vies for your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing to keep in mind is, when pitching an idea, article or “leak,” you need to keep in mind the potential to make a good headline. Although the headline doesn’t need to be a complete representation of what’s inside the article because “[o]utside of the subscription model, headlines are not intended to represent the contents of articles but to sell them—to win the fight for attention…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-7-killem-with-pageview-kindness&quot;&gt;Tactic #7: Kill’em With Pageview Kindness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want your brand to continue to get coverage with a blog, you’ll need to prove you can deliver pageviews. “Once your story has gotten coverage, one of the best ways to turn yourself into a favorite and regular subject is to make it clear your story is a reliable traffic draw. If you’re a brand, then post the story to your company Twitter and Facebook accounts and put it on your website. This inflates the stats in your favor and encourages more coverage down the road.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have much of a Twitter following, or you don’t want to publish the article to your audience, you can create your own buzz. “Blogs are so afraid of silence that the flimsiest of evidence can confirm they’re on the right track. You can provide this by leaving fake comments to articles about you or your company from blocked IP addresses—good and bad to make it clear that there is a hot debate. Send fake e-mails to the reporter, positive and negative. This rare kind of feedback cements the impression that you or your company make for high-valence material, and the blog should be covering you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And failing any of this, you can just buy the traffic. “At the penny-per-click rates of StumbleUpon and Outbrain, one hundred dollars means a rush of one thousand people or more—illusory confirmations to the blogger that you are newsworthy. The stat counters on these sites make no distinctions between fake and real views, nor does anyone care enough to dig deep into the sources of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-8-use-the-technology-against-itself&quot;&gt;Tactic #8: Use the Technology Against Itself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tactic 8 is rather bazaar—or perhaps I don’t understand it. The chapter talks about how the shorter the article the better it is likely to do online. That online, people aren’t willing to read more than about 800 words—about three pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holiday talks about how the constant requirement to publish also keeps the articles short because “no one wants to be the fool who wasted his or her time working on something nobody read.” And since posts are on the front page for only a few minutes at most news blogs, bloggers keep the word count down. Although I fail to see how Holiday uses this against the bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactic-9-just-make-stuff-up-everyone-else-is-doing-it&quot;&gt;Tactic #9: Just Make Stuff Up (Everyone Else is Doing It)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this chapter Holiday talks about how to get your mole-hill to be seen as a mountain. “Give a blogger an illusionary twenty-minute head start over other media sources, and they’ll write whatever you want[…]” What you want published doesn’t have to be big, relevant or even true but by manufacturing urgency, blogs will publish anything you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re having trouble getting bloggers to bite, you might try craigslist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A writer for the &lt;em&gt;Mediabistro&lt;/em&gt; blog &lt;em&gt;10,000 Words&lt;/em&gt; once advised new bloggers that they could find good material by scanning community bulletin boards on craigslist for “what people are complaining about these days.” I’m not a sociologist, but I’m pretty sure that doesn’t qualify as representative news. Considering that anyone can post anything on craigslist, this gives me a pretty good idea of how to create some fake local news. If they don’t mind seeing what isn’t there, I’m happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-two&quot;&gt;Book Two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped watching news TV and reading newspapers and news-magazines around 2006. When people ask me about it, I say that most of the “news” isn’t applicable to me and it’s not actionable—meaning I can’t do anything with the information. On top of that, 95% or more of what is written is negative and I feel much happier since removing it from my daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think this is crazy-talk and feel you need to stay informed, the second half of the book is filled with case studies and examples of people manipulating the media to promote their business or themselves. It shows how most of the news is fabricated or, at least, embellished to get pageviews on blogs and how big news outlets get their stories from these online publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for some new ways to promote your business, I wouldn’t follow Holiday’s actions in this book strictly—as he talks at length about how these tactics can come back to bit you. But you can learn from his tactics and alter them to fit your business—and hopefully alter them to be more ethical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/trust-me-im-lying-summary/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/trust-me-im-lying-summary/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Building Networks</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The richest people in the world look for and build networks, everyone else looks for work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/building-networks/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/building-networks/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Is &quot;Follow Your Passion&quot; Useful Advice?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/3001441/do-steve-jobs-did-dont-follow-your-passion&quot;&gt;Fast Company article&lt;/a&gt;, Cal Newport talks about how Steve Jobs became Steve Jobs of Apple instead of Steve Jobs of the Los Altos Zen Center. But just as in the presentation he gave at WDS, it leaves a lot of questions. It seems that after all his research there are still no answers about how to find work we love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All [Jobs’ story] tells us is that it’s good to enjoy what you do. This advice, though true, borders on the tautological and doesn’t help us with the pressing question that we actually care about: &lt;strong&gt;How do we find work that we’ll eventually love?&lt;/strong&gt; Like Jobs, should we resist settling into one rigid career and instead try lots of small schemes, waiting for one to take off? Does it matter what general field we explore? How do we know when to stick with a project or when to move on? In other words, &lt;strong&gt;Jobs’s story generates more questions than it answers.&lt;/strong&gt; Perhaps the only thing it does make clear is that, at least for Jobs, “follow your passion” was not particularly useful advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, can you predetermine passion for a career or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long suspected that you could. There are jobs, even though you’ve never done them, you know you wouldn’t like. If it’s possible to know which careers you wouldn’t like, it must be possible to determine careers that you would like. While Jobs couldn’t know that Apple was going to blow-up like it did, he knew he had an interest in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s assume that Cal’s research on finding passion is accurate—that it’s not good advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;pullright&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/images/So-Good-Newport.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;book cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For his new book, Cal conducted interviews looking for a consistency among those who like their jobs. The biggest factor for people who’d found “their calling,” was how long they had been in their industry. So if Cal is right, and there’s no way to predetermine passion, all the people who found their calling are either lucky or suffer from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://litemind.com/sunk-cost-bias/&quot;&gt;sunk cost bias&lt;/a&gt;. The sunk-cost group are lying to themselves because they don’t want to believe they’ve spent so much of their life on something meaningless. That group is easy enough to understand but what about the lucky group?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having yet to read the book I’m not sure if he tried to find a group that had spent many years in an industry but didn’t like their jobs. There are three groups that need to be interviewed to make this research whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who’ve found their calling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who have spent many years in an industry and are still unhappy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People that spent many years in a career that didn’t suit them but ultimately found something that did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only interviewing those that have found their calling is likely to produce a survivor’s bias. And only by interviewing all groups can we start to see patterns of what works and what doesn’t when picking a career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal’s conclusions from the interviews was, to have a meaningful career you need to stop looking for passion and get good at something rare and valuable. Once you’ve become good at something rare and valuable, you can obtain “traits” which will make all those years worth the effort. Things like autonomy, remote work agreements or part-time arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about people who have become rare and valuable and are still unhappy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;becoming-rare-and-valuable&quot;&gt;Becoming Rare and Valuable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing high school, I joined the US military and was assigned to work as a computer technician. I was sent to a three-month job training school covering all aspects of computer support. Later I was sent to another school to learn Unix support and after that, another school for the Defense Messaging System. I was also given a secret-level clearance so I could support both classified and unclassified systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After separating from the military I continued working with the Defense Messaging System for a government contractor. I then spent some years doing desktop support for private companies but later returned to government contracting. By the time I’d come back they had a new proprietary system call the Automated Message Handling System that had replaced the Defense Messaging System and I was sent to another training class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point in giving you my resume is to show how specialised my job was in the IT industry. Having a secret clearance and working on these systems put me in a very small, very specialized group. So without knowing it, I followed Cal’s “rare and valuable” advice, but after ten years I didn’t feel like I was any closer to gaining traits that would make the job feel like a calling or even make me happy I had the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-this-job-offer-those-traits&quot;&gt;Will This Job Offer Those Traits?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cal’s argument has a lot of merit. I’ve been thinking about it for a week and I can’t find fault with his comments—after all I’ve spent the last 8 years looking for my passion and have yet to find it. But his conclusions seem to be missing something. If I was able to spend ten years as a computer tech and not get the traits needed to feel like it was a calling, there are two possible problems. Either some jobs are unable to produce traits that are meaningful or I wasn’t good at the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Cal’s research has debunked the idea that passion can be predetermined, it leaves the questions “what traits will make me happy?” and “which careers will most likely produce, or allow for, those traits?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll agree with Cal on one thing, this research generates more questions than it answers. And it leaves me thinking that perhaps financial independence is the only way to happiness. That reducing your reliance on money will allow you to do those things that you’re passionate about but no one will pay you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update, July 2013: I finally got Cal’s book and did a summary and review which you can read here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/&quot;&gt;bradonomics.com/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/follow-passion-useful-advice/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/follow-passion-useful-advice/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Finding the Perfect Career: Passion or Pursuit</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following Cal Newport’s blog for a couple of years. I remember when he first started writing on the issue of how &lt;a href=&quot;http://calnewport.com/blog/2010/09/10/the-danger-of-the-dream-job-delusion/&quot;&gt;“follow your passion” might not be a good idea&lt;/a&gt;. I was a bit skeptical at the time and I’m still not sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has written a new book on the topic called So Good They Can’t Ignore You. While researching the book’s contents to see if it’s something worth reading, I found this video of Cal speaking about his research at the 2012 World Domination Summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/48041227?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video Cal gives an overview of his research. First is a story of Steve Jobs, in his first few years at university, his subsequent drop-out and working with Steve Wozniak on their first few projects. The conclusions drown from Jobs’ story, and a few other anecdotes, are that passion isn’t what leads most people into careers that they later say are meaningful or “a calling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second story is of Bill McKibben, a few years after graduating from Harvard when he decided to leave &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, move to Vermont and write &lt;em&gt;The End of Nature&lt;/em&gt;. Bill’s story is where Cal gives alternative advice to following passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says there are two steps to finding meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get good at something rare and valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use that as leverage to gain the things (or traits) that matter to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In McKibben’s case Cal speculates that he wanted simplicity, autonomy and to have an impact. By moving to a cabin in the Vermont woods he had simplicity, by writing he had autonomy and, because he was a good writer, he had impact in the environmental movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McKibben started developed skills while working for the &lt;em&gt;The Harvard Crimson&lt;/em&gt; newspaper, then continued developing those skills working for &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;. Had McKibben not been a good writer he wouldn’t have gotten an advance sufficient to move to Vermont and write the book. And then Cal cautions of two pitfalls in getting the traits that will make your career meaningful:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you try to get the traits without first being valuable, your chances of succeeding drop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’re valuable, that’s when you’ll have the most pressure to stick on the path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in his previous articles, he suggests that what you do is much less important than you think when looking for meaning in your career. That you’ll be just as happy in one job as another, so long as you’re able to have traits that are important to you—which only come after you’re valuable to someone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/finding-the-perfect-career/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/finding-the-perfect-career/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Jobs for Travelers</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy reading interesting stories from interesting people and it seems most people doing interesting things are doing them on the road. If you go back to the start of many travel blogs you’ll read about the prep stages of the blogger’s journey. How long they saved for the trip or the arrangements made before they left. Some of them even talk about trying to find a job or business that will sustain them while traveling. Some of the most common things travelers talk about when discussing businesses they can run from the road are affiliate marketing schemes or teaching English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affiliate marketing is most often manifested by travel bloggers as Google Adsense or hotel reviews or travel insurance sales. Some of the more diligent bloggers have arranged direct advertising based on their page views and have a more consistent income. I’m not saying affiliate marketing is a bad idea, but it’s hard to build momentum. What happens when nothing exciting has happened lately and you don’t feel like writing? What happens if you get sick and can’t look at your computer for more than two minutes? If your income is tied to your pages views, the money is going to slow if you stop writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching English is big business in Asia and a lot of people think they’ll use that as a way to travel for a year or two. I’ve been in Asia for three years as of this writing and I feel little difference between living here and living in the US. Sure I’ve got a temple with tigers walking the grounds two hours drive from my house but after a week of commuting in Bangkok traffic I don’t feel like going. It’s a common feeling among English teachers I know. They might like the exoticness of the country but they’re not enjoying it as much as they assumed they would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-not-blogging-or-teaching-what&quot;&gt;If Not Blogging or Teaching, What?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if not this, what else is possible to do from the road? With the technology available to you, the only thing stopping you is your mind. You can set up forwarding on a US phone number and it will ring to your cell phone in Bangkok—or in the Himalayan mountains, or wherever you want to be. You can send invoices and documents via email or Google docs or any other online service and no one would know it was sent from an island in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an idea I’ve got for travelers. With six months of part-time study, you could learn enough HTML, CSS, and PHP to develop your own WordPress themes. And since you’re a traveler, you know what travelers are looking for that other developers don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming a $1,000 per month baseline, and knowing that the average theme on &lt;a href=&quot;http://themeforest.net/&quot;&gt;Themeforest&lt;/a&gt; goes for around $50, you’ll need to sell 40 themes per month to have an indefinite runway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;runway&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;—noun&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How long you can afford to live without getting a job.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might seem like a lot, especially if you don’t know how to design WordPress themes yet and don’t know anything about marketing. But what are you going to do over the next year? You could keep working in your cubicle, eating ramen and saving all your pennies hoping to stay on the road for six months straight. Or you could spend your evenings and weekends learning to code and design WordPress templates and stay gone forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-this-different-from-blogging&quot;&gt;How Is This Different From Blogging?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking that this is no better than blogging. Won’t the money stop if I stop writing code, just as it would if I stopped writing prose? It would, but it would take longer to dry completely. I assume you’d be offering some type of support for your themes, but even if you offered the themes “as-is,” people would still buy them. Once the marketing machine is working, you’ll need very little to keep the sales coming—enough sales to keep your $1,000/month anyway. Your existing advertising or your affiliates would take care of the inbound traffic and as long as your designs are good and function as described, you’ll continue to make sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;picking-a-specialty-to-grow-your-business&quot;&gt;Picking a Specialty to Grow Your Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gotten a good understanding of front-end development you could specialize in one type of theme or one type of framework. Take &lt;a href=&quot;http://kolakube.com/&quot;&gt;Alex Mangini&lt;/a&gt; for instance, he only works with Thesis. Or what about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.briangardner.com/&quot;&gt;Brian Gardner&lt;/a&gt;, he founded StudioPress, partnered with Copyblogger Media and only designs with his &lt;a href=&quot;https://my.studiopress.com/themes/genesis/&quot;&gt;Genesis Framework&lt;/a&gt;. These guys have carved a niche for themselves and are top of mind when people need work with Thesis or Genesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gotten more comfortable you can carve your own niche, and why not make travel themes since you’re going to be traveling? It’s like I said before, you know what travelers need since you’re one of them. To give you some ideas of where you can start, here is a theme I wish someone would build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most travelers start their trips on day-one, and after that day-two, and continue in that fashion till they reach the end of their trip. But most blog pagination doesn’t allow me to follow in that order. When I look at the pagination of most blogs I start on page one, which in this case means the most recent entries. Even if I go to “last” it’s not as easy as it could be to follow the journey from the beginning. And the standard pagination isn’t as visually appealing as most traveler bloggers wish it was, but it’s all we’ve got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;/images/pagination.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pagination for Travel Blogger Theme&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only theme that’s doing anything close is &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2011/08/04/new-theme-chapters/&quot;&gt;Chapters by WooThemes&lt;/a&gt;. It was designed for authors who want to publish books online. You can follow by chapters in this theme the same way I’d like to follow days in your journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of which, haven’t you been reading a lot of travel blogs in preparation for your trip? That’s not as easy as it could be either, right? I’ve yet to find an app that will let me rip the whole archives of a website, in chronological order, and save it to my Kindle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; is close in that it allows you to save articles in .mobi or .epub format, but it doesn’t have the functionality to rip a whole site. I’d pay for an app like this (if you build one, get in touch). PHP alone wouldn’t be all that’s required for this type of app but you could charge a monthly fee for the service, allowing your marketing efforts to be reduced significantly and your runway to be infinite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jobs-for-travelers/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jobs-for-travelers/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Blogs I Wish You&apos;d Start</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are not enough good periodicals. The only magazine I’ve found to be consistently good is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sunset.com/&quot;&gt;Sunset&lt;/a&gt;. I had a subscription when I was in the States and would read cover-to-cover each month. I’m always on the lookout for good magazines, blogs, and podcasts. Since I’m consistently disappointed with the offerings, I thought I’d talk about what separates the good from the mediocre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it easier for me to write and easier for you to read, I’m going to use the word &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; when I’m not talking about a specific platform. That doesn’t mean that these ideas are only suitable in written form and only suitable for the web. If you prefer, you can change the name to magazine, podcast, video blog, or whatever you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First let’s talk about two blogs that have almost got it. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/&quot;&gt;Mr Money Mustache&lt;/a&gt; who I think has a great concept. No one else is talking about this level of frugality that doesn’t want us to live in grass huts. Mr Money Mustache lives in the city, has a normal house, a car, and still managed to retire in his 30s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While his design leaves much to be desired, I think what’s holding him back most is his writing style. Since he’s an engineer by trade I assume he didn’t spend a lot of time writing before starting the blog. He seems like a dick. Someone I wouldn’t want over for dinner and probably wouldn’t want to have drinks with. I don’t know if his personality doesn’t show in his writing or if shows all too well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another blog that has almost got it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://flagtheory.com/&quot;&gt;Flag Theory&lt;/a&gt;. Due to the nature of the website, Edmund, the author, is very vague. It’s hard to build rapport with someone who refuses to put personality in his writing. I understand when you’re writing about getting second passports and how best to avoid taxes, you’d like to remain anonymous but there’s got to be a way to do that and still write with personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I think would make his blog better, and get me to add it back to my RSS reader, is to drop the conspiracy theory talk. You appeal to a certain crowd with those topics and I don’t think that’s the crowd he’s looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://manvsdebt.com/&quot;&gt;Man vs Debt&lt;/a&gt;, although it doesn’t resonate with me, is very popular. It follows Adam Baker and his family in their journey to pay-off debt, pare down their possessions, and travel. Adam writes in an authentic voice, which is a must for a successful online publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about a blog that has cracked the code. Dan Andrews runs a site called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tropicalmba.com/&quot;&gt;Tropical MBA&lt;/a&gt;. He started the blog in 2009 to recruit western talent to Asia. He offered internships with his company and used the blog to promote them. He’s offered nine so far but these days he’s writing much more about his thoughts on business, how he’s been traveling for the past 4-5 years while running a hard-goods manufacturing business and offering his best insights on how you can do the same. His writing style is compelling and his tips are actionable. There’s nothing Dan publishes that I don’t read. Whatever the secret sauce is, he’s found it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of podcasting, I think it’s a platform that’s going to blow-up in the next ten years. There are some pretty famous people already making their on-air radio shows available on the web or who’ve left radio for podcasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think, after looking over the blogs listed above, I only like business content. But they are the only ones that are killin’ it. And that’s why I’m writing this, I want you to create something as good as these guys in another category. And to that end, here are some ideas I think would do well. I don’t know how much money is to be made from the first two, and maybe that’s why they don’t exist, but I have little doubt there’d be an audience for all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;House-sitting or Caretaking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to read a blog about someone traveling around the world and using something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caretaker.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Caretaker Gazette&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trustedhousesitters.com/&quot;&gt;Trusted House Sitters&lt;/a&gt; to do so. Stories about the trips, what it’s like house sitting, how to find good properties and good property owners, how to structure your affairs before leaving home—a completely different take on long-term travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing research for this article it looks like &lt;a href=&quot;http://moderndaynomads.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;someone was doing this but has since stopped&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WWOOFing around the world&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very similar to the house sitting example—only on farms. Same types of information and stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Expat Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been looking four months for information on starting a business in Thailand. There’s very little information on the different legal structures and there’s no stories of other entrepreneurs who’ve started successful businesses. Something like this could even start a community and spawn a paid forum to support the writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bicycle Tours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve found a few blogs like this but I’d love to see more. My favorite is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbiking.info/wordpress/&quot;&gt;World Biking&lt;/a&gt;, a husband and wife team making their way around the world on two wheels. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bicycletouringpro.com/&quot;&gt;Bicycle Touring Pro&lt;/a&gt; focuses mostly on Europe. &lt;a href=&quot;http://japancyclingtrip.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;A Singaporean Cycling Across Japan&lt;/a&gt; is years out of date, but still good reading. I’d love to see more cycling blogs. Maybe something location specific—how a city is adding bike lanes and paths and notes for other municipalities to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christian Graugart did a world tour in 2011 and chronicled the journey on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bjjglobetrotters.com/&quot;&gt;BJJ Globetrotters&lt;/a&gt;. Then there’s Can Sönmez who occasionally &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideyfoot.com/search/label/travel&quot;&gt;travels for jiu-jitsu&lt;/a&gt;. Most good jiu-jitsu blogs have folded. I’m not sure if it’s the prevalence of Big Social or that writing is harder than rambling on video or what. If you’re playing jiu-jitsu, please, please, please start writing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know some good blogs I should check out, please email me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/start-blogs/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/start-blogs/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The $100 Million Question</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at dinner with a friend who works as a tour guide. He was telling me about the parts of his job he dislikes. About how he’ll tell his guests the day’s events; what they’ll be seeing, where they’ll be eating lunch, etc. He said that within five minutes someone always asks where they’re going or where they’re eating lunch and how it drives him mad to repeat himself. I thought about this for a few days and the only thing I can figure is, he’s in the wrong profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most jobs are the same things over-and-over. Businessmen pitch the same product every day, telling the same stories. Technicians fix the same problems, plumbers unclog drains, in most industries people do the same things every day. If you don’t like your product enough to talk about it every day, you’re going to be miserable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that’s you. Maybe you’re miserable and you want to leave your job, but how do you know if the new job will be any better? I’ve got a question, while difficult to answer, might give you some insight. There are two ways this question can be asked, and it depends on your mental state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re completely miserable in your job I’m going to give you $100 million dollars so you can leave. You get to use the money for two years. The only things you can’t buy are investments; no real estate with the intent to rent or resale, no stocks, no bonds. You can start a business if you like or go back to school, but here’s the deal, after two years the money you haven’t used must be returned. If you’ve decided to return to school, you’ll have to have finished or you’ll have to pay for the rest by yourself. If you started a business it has to be self-sustaining at that point. If you decided to travel and just relax, you now have to return to your life as it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not miserable in your job the question is different. Perhaps your job is OK—not great, but not miserable. You still get the same $100 million, but you get it for five years …and then you die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick which situation matches yours and then ask yourself what you’d do. Who would you meet, where would you go, what would you do there? If you keep a journal, look through it and see if there are things you’ve been writing about for years, it could give you direction in your thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has things, like my friend, they don’t want to talk about every day; things they don’t want to repeat continually. But then there are things you do talk about all the time and wouldn’t mind repeating. Don’t think about things you’re good at, that can be misleading. I spent 10 years in IT support and while I can talk intelligently on the subject, I don’t like talking about computers—at least in that capacity. Explaining why you can’t print to the same people every day is why I left the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about the things you love talking about. Things you corner strangers with. I love language learning. I love talking about how language is learned, why adults tend to have accents and children don’t, why I think adults start speaking their target language too soon. I tell everyone—friends and people I’ve just met. I’ll even buy you a coffee just to be able to talk about it again. The same goes for Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you find something like this it’s time to start asking if it’s possible to make money from it, but first think about &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;, then we can think about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;following-cash-flows&quot;&gt;Following Cash Flows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t got a good answer from the $100 million question, stick with it until you do. If you start thinking about how to make money before you think about what’s really important you’re likely to continue doing work you don’t like—only in a different industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got an idea of what you want to do, what you want your Wikipedia page to say when you’re dead, you have to decide if you want to do this as an employee or as the business owner. Doing it as an employee is easier. You can take the ideas you’ve generated, enter them into a website like &lt;a href=&quot;http://careerassessmentsite.com/&quot;&gt;Career Assessment Site&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onetonline.org/&quot;&gt;O*Net&lt;/a&gt; and it will tell you what industries best fit your interests. Those same websites will often show you available jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you want to be the business owner? Things are less defined for entrepreneurs. A good place to start is looking for established cash flows in the industry where you’d like to work. This isn’t a 100% always-true rule, but there’s a good chance if no one’s making money with the products or services you’re thinking of, there’s no money to be made with those products or services. Venkat from Ribbon Farm has a great article on this called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ribbonfarm.com/2010/11/05/ancient-rivers-of-money/&quot;&gt;Ancient Rivers of Money&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not a big Venkat fan, but that article is really good and worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for things people are already paying for in your industry. Can you make improvements on these? Do you know of a cheaper manufacturing process? Can you provide better customer service? Is your approach to providing the product unique? Can you offer free shipping? All of these have been used by other business before to define their unique sales proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t have to be world-changing. Maybe you can look at the processes from another industry and bring them to your own. A manufacturing process from another industry that would give you a unique position. A payment system from another industry that will make it easier for your customers, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What might be even better is to just get a job first. After you’ve spent a few years in this new field you’ll be better able to introduce some innovation. But it’ll take some time in the industry and some work—the type of work &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you-book-review/&quot;&gt;you’ll only put in if you love it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/100-million-dollar-question/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/100-million-dollar-question/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>A New Business Model for Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;You show up to an academy, try a class for free, and if you like it you’ll be asked to sign a contract with the school. Most schools do 6-month or 1-year contracts. Most schools ask for some type of electronic funds transfer. And remember, you’ll be paying this fee for as long as you attend the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not a bad model necessarily. Most schools are using it. I understand there are bills to be paid—rent, utilities, etc.—and then there’s the instructor’s compensation. But should the students need to pay for five, six, seven years if they choose to stick around that long? The obvious answer is, of course, if they’re using the facilities they should pay for them. But what if the students could pay less while the school owner made more money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School owners know how many students they have, but it’s surprising how many don’t know other statistics about their business. I’ve asked a few people the number of classes the average student takes per week and no one has ever known for sure. I’ve asked how long the average student stays with the school and no one has ever known that either. I’m sure some of the larger schools that are managed by a team would know, but the &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; school owner doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t thought about business models for martial arts schools till &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bjjweekly.com/blog/post/phil-migliarese-free-jiu-jitsu-training-for-everyone-is-he-nuts&quot;&gt;Phil Migliarese was on &lt;em&gt;BJJ Weekly&lt;/em&gt; talking about his 90-days-free program&lt;/a&gt;. I’d never heard of anything like this before. Most schools offer one day free, a few offer one month as a sales gimmick—only giving you the month once you’ve signed a year contract, but I’d never heard of anyone offering three months of training for free. Phil said it was because of an economic slump. He wanted to give people a chance to try Jiu-Jitsu that would otherwise be hesitant to add another bill to their family’s budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listened to the whole show and thought about this new model. Then I thought about the current model and asked myself two questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would be the best model from a patron perspective?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would be the best model from an owner perspective?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an owner I’d want enough tuition payments to cover rent, utilities, insurance, and my own salary. I’d want some assurance that these payments were going to be coming every month, and I’d want to reduce churn as much as possible. I’d spend enough time marketing the school to ensure, at the very least, for every student I lost I’d gain a new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a student of martial arts I want good instruction and a clean academy. I want to pay as little as possible and I don’t want a long-term contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being as no one has ever told me how long the average Jiu-Jitsu player stays at a school, I’ll guess for the sake of this article. Getting to blue belt isn’t particularly difficult but most people never make it to purple. I’ll assume they stay for a year and a half. My best guess is that they don’t want to pay for it after that—whether it’s the money itself or the diminishing returns on their training, I’m not sure. I’ve played at more than a handful of schools and each time I’ve left it was because of money. I have no stats to prove this but I suspect money is the biggest reason people leave Jiu-Jitsu academies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason, one thing is certain—they’re leaving. I think it’s time to implement the exact opposite of 90-days-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our scenario, school owners are getting 18 months of tuition payments from their average student. The school owner then has to spend time marketing the school in order to replace those students. Wouldn’t it be great if they could keep those senior students? But how do you do this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you’re only getting 18 months of payments from the average student, what if you could get 24? At $100 dollars per month, your average student payments would go from $1,800 to $2,400—a 33% increase. I think you could do this by front loading your payment plan. Charge for the first two years of classes and after that, it’s free for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people will still feel like leaving at around 18 months but knowing they can be a lifetime member by sticking around only six more, they likely will stick around. The school owner gets more money per student than they would otherwise and students can see a light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My numbers could be off and if you’ve been tracking how long your students stay, you can adjust these numbers to better fit your school. Maybe your average student stays for only one year, or maybe they stay for three. In any case, the plan still works—you get more money per student than you would otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear thoughts about this model. If you’ve tried something like this or plan to try, please email me. I’d be very interested in your results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/bjj-business-model/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/bjj-business-model/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Thoughts on Publishing and Finding a Calling</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the early 2000s, I had a dream to be a professional fighter. In December of 2005 I had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mixedmartialarts.com/fighter/Brad-West:76B048FA2791855A/&quot;&gt;my first&lt;/a&gt; (and to date, only) Mixed Martial Arts fight and I realized that I liked the idea of being a fighter but not the reality of going to the gym every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to Thailand with the intent to start a business. I knew I wanted to start something that I could take with me—something I could do from anywhere. I’ve spent hundreds of hours thinking of different industries, what I could bring to the market and what I’d really like to be doing with my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of “Lifestyle Design” talk is about finding and following your passion. Recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tropicalmba.com/our-mindset-manifesto/&quot;&gt;Dan Andrews gave his thoughts on the topic&lt;/a&gt;. He said that people are often looking for an &lt;em&gt;industry&lt;/em&gt; that is a calling when they should be looking for &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; that is a calling. Every industry has accountants and every industry has salesmen. If you enjoy selling you can do it for any industry and be happy; but if you love the travel industry yet hate selling, you’ll be miserable as a salesman even if you’re doing it for a travel company—just as I was going to the gym every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of blogging or publishing in general. It’s something I can take anywhere and it’s something with a lot of variety. I could publish a blog on business or a podcast on fighting or a magazine about travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of magazines, have you seen some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2010/05/micro-magazines-and-a-future-of-media.html&quot;&gt;micro-magazines&lt;/a&gt; being published lately? There’s Fear-Less, which looks defunct, but was free and relied on advertisements to pay the writers. Mountain &amp;amp; Pacific produced paid publications for the better part of two years. Then there’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.southeastasiabackpacker.com/&quot;&gt;Southeast Asia Backpacker&lt;/a&gt;, supported by ads and is available online and in print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think publishing in this capacity will continue to grow—niche topics serving smaller audiences. People are looking for things not available on TV or the newsstand. Very niche topics that aren’t being served. Advertisers are having a hard time with the mass markets that TV networks and newspapers draw and because of this, niche publishers are getting more attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s a great time to get into the publishing industry if you’re interested in doing something niche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update March 2015:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not sure this is true anymore. Besides two of the three examples having folded since I first wrote this, all the smaller publications I know of are struggling. I think there’s still opportunities in publishing from a business perspective, but you better have a plan before you start—and ads are not a good strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/thoughts-on-publishing-and-finding-a-calling/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/thoughts-on-publishing-and-finding-a-calling/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Embarrassing Questions</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Asking questions is embarrassing for a moment, but not asking is embarrassing for a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;cite&quot;&gt;—Haruki Murakami&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/embarrassing-questions/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/embarrassing-questions/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>How to Succeed at Art</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman addresses the University of the Arts class of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe title=&quot;How to Succeed at Art&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/42372767?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/how-to-succeed-at-art/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/how-to-succeed-at-art/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Building a Fitness Company in Thailand</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Some months ago I was introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.megangebhart.com/about/&quot;&gt;Megan Gebhart&lt;/a&gt; and her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.52cups.com/&quot;&gt;52 Cups of Coffee&lt;/a&gt; project. I contacted Megan to ask how the two interviews she did over Skype differed from the fifty she did in person. Since I live in Thailand and a lot of the entrepreneurs I know, I only know from the internet, I assumed I’d be doing many interviews over Skype if I did a 52-Cups-like project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Megan encouraged me to do the project but said that doing the interviews over Skype wasn’t as good as doing them in person. She said it was harder to build rapport through the computer. She suggested that I try to meet people locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask me, I tell them I’m an aspiring entrepreneur. I have no experience in launching anything and have no friends or family who are entrepreneurs. So hearing about Megan’s project made me think I should do something similar while I’m still at university. I could meet with people, fill the gaps in my education and learn entrepreneurship from people who’ve done it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have very few connections I started my search for entrepreneurs on LinkedIn. While I want to meet people from a variety of industries, I wanted to ease into this. I wanted my first meeting to be easy. I didn’t want to meet someone with nothing in common outside of entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-rich-thurman&quot;&gt;Enter Rich Thurman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;pullright&quot; src=&quot;/images/Rich-Thurman.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coach Rich Thurman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found Rich on Twitter (back when I used to have a Twitter account). I don’t remember if it was because he posted about a local MMA event or if someone @replied him about the event, but I quickly found his LinkedIn profile and saw that he owned a fitness company in Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect, I thought. We’re both from the States, we’re about the same age and, if all else fails, we can talk about MMA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met Rich and his partner Faz at Dean &amp;amp; Deluca’s outside the Ploenchit BTS station. They’d just come from another meeting and were dressed in slacks and nice button-down shirts. There I was in jeans and a tee-shirt and I instantly thought “dress for the job you want, not the job you have.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich told me about what the last five years have been like in Thailand. We talked about the struggle he had developing the concept of his company. Then the struggle he’s had building his company. He told me that looking back on it, connections have meant everything in growing his business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told me about going to networking events and meeting other entrepreneurs and how these people introduced him to more people. It all gives me encouragement that I’m on the right path with these meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update October 2013:&lt;/strong&gt; Rich returned to the US only a few months after our meeting. In a private chat via Facebook, I asked Rich how he felt about the move. He said that while he missed the warm weather he didn’t miss Thailand and told me it was so much easier running a business in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself in San Francisco and in need of a trainer check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coachrichthurman.com/&quot;&gt;Rich’s homepage&lt;/a&gt; or his gym, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xodusfitness.com/&quot;&gt;Xodus Fitness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/rich-thurman/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/rich-thurman/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Jeff Joslin on Keeping a Journal for MMA Training</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;pullright&quot; src=&quot;/images/jeff-joslin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeff Joslin in a Jiu-Jitsu Gi&quot; /&gt;
In 2009 or so I had a dream to start a podcast called White Belt Radio. I bought the domain name, reserved the Twitter and Facebook handles, but I sat on the project for too long and another company started publishing under that name. I decided to change the name but carry on with the original intent of the show and in 2011 I started a podcast called FightMap. The podcast is now defunct but I enjoyed this talk with Jeff Joslin so much I wanted it available somewhere on the web. So here it is, as it ran on FightMap, on Bradonomics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some years ago I was on YouTube when I found a video of Jeff Joslin showing his 700-page Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu journal. As soon as the video was over I wanted to talk with Jeff. I had so many questions about training when you didn’t live near a big team, or any Jiu-Jitsu team at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; src=&quot;/audio/FightMap-004-Jeff-Joslin.mp3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/audio/FightMap-004-Jeff-Joslin.mp3&quot;&gt;Right-click here and “save file as” to download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mentions&quot;&gt;Mentions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oKA4dPAMk7E&quot;&gt;700-page Jiu-Jitsu Journal Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mobile.twitter.com/JeffJoslin&quot;&gt;Jeff on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jeffjoslinmma.com/my-story/&quot;&gt;Jeff’s Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/jeff-joslin-mma-journal/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/jeff-joslin-mma-journal/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>An Ode To Chicken Legs</title>
          <description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;In Memory of Hollis Hudetz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/images/hollis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hollis Hudetz holding me somewhere in Los Angeles&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Ode To Chicken Legs By Hollis Hudetz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dainty little chicken legs &lt;br /&gt;
pokin’ out like wooden pegs &lt;br /&gt;
get me where I want to go &lt;br /&gt;
through the hills and creeks and snow. &lt;br /&gt;
Should I e’er get in a fight &lt;br /&gt;
my enemy will see my might &lt;br /&gt;
does not reside down there below &lt;br /&gt;
and so that’s where he’ll aim his blows. &lt;br /&gt;
But verily to his surprise &lt;br /&gt;
my bony knees will WHACK his thighs! &lt;br /&gt;
And ever will he curse the day &lt;br /&gt;
that chicken legs came out to play. &lt;br /&gt;
And too it’s better there’s no meat- &lt;br /&gt;
it gives the beasts nothing to eat! &lt;br /&gt;
So they will let me pass on by &lt;br /&gt;
and never once I’ll catch their eye. &lt;br /&gt;
So better off I think you’ll be &lt;br /&gt;
if you have chicken legs, like me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/ode-to-chicken-legs/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/ode-to-chicken-legs/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Parkinson&apos;s Law and Language Learning</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://bradonomics.com/brown-autobiography/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;From the Outside In&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Dr. J. Marvin Brown. It’s a memoir about Dr. Brown’s “language life.” In the book he talks about studying linguistics at the University of Utah, the University of California and Cornell University. He talks about being sent to Thailand to participate in a language learning experiment, and his work at the AUA school in Bangkok and how he developed the Automatic Language Growth (ALG) method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he was first sent to Thailand, he was sent to complete the second part of a language learning experiment known as the Army Method. It was an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audio-lingual_method&quot;&gt;audio-lingual method&lt;/a&gt; where a student spent one year in a classroom repeating words, phrases, and sentences and then moved to an immersion environment for reinforcement. In Dr. Brown’s case, it was Thai language and he was sent to Bangkok. The assumption was he’d return to the US fluent in Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After one year his pronunciation was good but he struggled to construct sentences and had a hard time in conversation. He was understood but was nothing close to a native speaker—which is what the experiment was intended to produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the year was over he informed the staff at his university that the experiments were a success and that his pronunciation was indeed native-like. His misuse of the language was of no consequence and years later he would use Parkinson’s Law to explain his reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson&apos;s_Law&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s Law&lt;/a&gt; states: Work expands to fill the time available for its completion. While reflecting on the reports about the “success” of his experiments he realized that Parkinson’s Law could be stated another way: Goals shrink to fit performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I speak to people about natural methods of language learning I’m always asked about grammar. Once I explain that there is no conscious study of grammar, no translation of words or sentences to the students native language they argue that this method would never work—that without the study of grammar, a language could not be learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would wonder why people thought this way and recently learned the reason. The people I was talking with had invested in a grammar-based, translation approach. They had spent time, money and much effort in that system and refused to think it wouldn’t produce the results they were told. It’s the same problem Dr. Brown had, it’s why he sent the report that the experiments were a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it seems that we’ve shrunk the goals. We’ve stopped using the native speaker as the mark of success and started using other learners. Deciding that failing less than others means success. Dr. Brown says it this way: “Learning,” as opposed to whatever children do, puts us on crutches, and the competition is to see who can use crutches best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what to say to people who want to use a translation approach to language learning because, after all, it is faster in the initial stages. The only advice I can offer is, don’t let short-term satisfaction blind you to long term goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
          <link>https://bradonomics.com/parkinsons-law-and-language-learning/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradonomics.com/parkinsons-law-and-language-learning/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
